我在138街的办公室里工作。
I was working in my office on 138th Street.
主要是治疗一战中受伤的人，比如我。
Mostly fixing up banged-up guys, like myself, from the Great War.
看到了吗?美丽。
See? Beautiful.
所有的伤害都是世界乐于忘记的。
All from injuries the world was happy to forget.
修整面部，振奋精神，唱歌。
Fixing faces, lifting spirits, singing songs.
花生我的眼睛落在法国了。
Peanuts I left my eye in France.
我经常因为尝试研发新药而被医学委员会留校察看。
And I was constantly on probation with the medical board for trying to make new medicines.
我的意思是，我们需要当时还不存在的药物来度过痛苦和紧张的一天。
I mean, we needed medicines that didn't exist yet just to get through the day, with the pain and the nerves.
我希望这是一种更好的药。这就是我要说的。
I hope this is a better pill. That's all I'm saying.
我希望你是对的。
I hope you're right.
有些人比其他人做得更好。
Some worked better than others.
这是我今天的第二天。
This is my second of the day.
我感觉很好。
And I feel great.
维克多，你想尝尝吗?
Victor, you wanna try one?
是的。我下周会试试新的。
Yeah. I'll try the new one next week.
好吧。这会给你活力。
All right. That gives you zing.
把裤子穿上，伯特。我帮你修好了。
Put your pants on, Burt. I repaired 'em for you.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
因为我在战争中受伤，我的背部有一个我讨厌的支架。
Because of my war injuries, I had a back brace I hated.
如果他们不把这地方关了他们就会把你关起来。
They're gonna put you away if they don't close this place down.
那没用，雪莉。
That's not helpful, Shirley.
实验医学。
Experimental medicine.
你看起来不错。
You look good.
-感染怎么样了?-好吧。
- How's the infection? - All right.
好，好，好，好，好。
Good, good, good, good, good.
我明白了。
And I got the message.
还不需要付钱。
No need to pay yet.
伯特，你有留言。
Burt, you got messages.
你父母打电话来了。他们不能去度假了。
Your parents called. They can't make the holiday.
赫伯·盖兹打电话来问滴耳液的事。
Herb Getz called about the ear drops.
哈罗德·伍德曼打来电话。在这个地址和他见面。
And Harold Woodman called. Meet him at this address.
直接走进去。紧迫。
Walk right in. Urgent.
我和一个律师一起工作，他是我战时最好的朋友，哈罗德·伍德曼。
I worked with an attorney, my best friend from the war, Harold Woodman.
嘿,伯特。
Hey, Burt.
这是怎么回事?这是什么地方?
What is going on? What is this place?
-这案子很重要。——是吗?
- It's a very important case. - Yeah?
-报酬非常丰厚。——好。
- Pays very handsomely. - Nice.
我们有很多未付的账单。
We have a lot of back bills.
人们依赖我们，依赖我们的生意。
People depend on us, our business.
最重要的是，它对你我都很有意义。
Most importantly, it's very meaningful to both you and I.
有意义如何?
Meaningful how?
你关心的是年度晚会，不是吗?-是的。
Well, you care about the annual gala, - don't you? - Yeah.
你总说我们退伍军人聚会很重要，被人记住。-是的。
And you always say it's important for us vets to have reunions, - to be remembered. - It is.
你说我们聚在一起唱歌是一剂良药。你不这么说吗?
And you say it's great medicine for us to get together and sing. Don't you say that?
这是怎么回事?
Where's this going?
这是一个特定的程序，我知道你喜欢某些程序。
It's going to a particular procedure, and I know how you prefer some procedures over others.
告诉我是什么。
Just tell me what it is.
什么……什么样的程序?
What... What kind of procedure?
你拿这些花干什么?
What are you doing with these flowers?
和碧翠丝的晚餐约会。
Dinner date with Beatrice.
-和碧翠丝的晚餐约会?——是的。
- Dinner date with Beatrice? - Yes.
-太令人失望了。-她是我妻子。
- So disappointing. - She's my wife.
他能做这个手术吗?
Is he all right to perform the procedure?
是的。他……他是。没关系。
Yes. He... He is. It's okay.
-他不会这么做的-他会这么做的
- He's not gonna do it. - He's gonna do it.
-冷静点。-你是谁?
- Calm down. - Who is this?
这是莉兹·米金斯，伯特。
This is Liz Meekins, Burt.
Meekins吗?例如，关于……他是我的父亲。我知道你很崇拜他。
Meekins? As in, relation to... He's my father. I know you admire him very much.
-我的天啊。是的。-我们都是。做的。
- Oh, my God. Yes. - We both did. Do.
真的。
I really do.
这就是为什么他要在我们今年的同学会上讲话。
That's why he's gonna speak at our reunion this year.
很高兴见到你。
Very nice to meet you.
我们要在这里见你父亲吗?
Are we meeting your father here?
让她说完，伯特。
Let her finish, Burt.
我父亲昨天坐船回来的。
My father came back yesterday on a boat.
好的。他去欧洲出差了，对吧?
Okay. He goes to Europe on business, right?
他是被虫子咬了还是怎么了?
Did he catch a bug or something?
我来看看他。他在哪里?
I'll look at him. Where is he?
你应该看看他。
You should see him.
是的。来吧。我们走吧。
Yeah. Come on. Let's go.
这地方真漂亮。看看它。
This place is gorgeous. Look at it.
所以,……那个"安静不动"的比尔将军呢?
So, where... where is, uh, the good General "Quiet and Still" Bill?
原谅我。
Excuse me.
我今天过敏得厉害。
My allergies are terrible today.
我一觉醒来，鼻窦里都是，一整天都是。
I wake up, it's in my sinus, and it's the whole day.
我不知道你在干什么，我也不想知道你在干什么。
I don't know what you're doing, and I don't wanna know what you're doing.
两小时后，防腐师就会来了。
You have two hours until the embalmer comes.
发生了什么事?他本来要在晚会上讲话的。
What happened? He was gonna speak at the gala.
你会帮我的，是吗?
You will help me, won't you?
我不相信他是自然死亡。
I'm not buying that he died of natural causes.
他是个非常健康的人。
He was a very healthy man.
我家里没人同意我的看法。
No one in my family agrees with me.
他们都错了。他们都是骗子。
They're all wrong. They're all liars.
我要尸检。
I want an autopsy.
这是正确的。这是你的权利。
That's correct. It is your right.
你父亲没有留下遗嘱就去世了。
Your father died intestate.
你是他的近亲。我看了报纸。
You're the next of kin. I read the papers.
我讨厌验尸，哈罗德。你知道的。
I hate autopsies, Harold. You know that.
我们必须这么做，伯特。
We have to do it, Burt.
比尔·"安静与宁静"·米金斯是我们相遇的原因。
Bill "Quiet and Still" Meekins is the reason we met.
他组建了我们的团。
He formed our regiment.
这样的人怎么会死了?
How did a man like this end up dead?
你是说这很可疑?
You're telling me it's suspicious?
是的，我告诉你这很可疑。
Yes, I'm telling you it's suspicious.
你愿意和我一起唱吗?
Will you please sing with me?
他说你打仗的时候经常和他一起唱歌。
He said that you used to sing with him when you were at war.
他非常喜欢。
He enjoyed it so much.
珍贵的回忆看不见的天使从某处送到我的灵魂快点。
- Precious memories - HAROLD: Memories Unseen angels Sent from somewhere to my soul Hurry up.
你只有两个小时去做你想做的事。
You only have two hours to do whatever it is you're gonna do.
好吧。你得去做尸检，然后马上到明特斯餐厅找我。
All right. You have to do the autopsy, and immediately after, meet me at Minters Restaurant.
我要知道你找到了什么。
I need to know what you find.
她为什么说两个小时?
Why did she say two hours?
因为我们在殡仪馆。
Because we're in the mortician.
他们会让他下葬的。
They're gonna put him in the ground.
明特餐厅，5点后。
Minters Restaurant, after 5:00.
你得把他弄出去。
You've gotta get him out of here.
我们该走了，伯特。
Yeah, we should get going, Burt.
哈罗德?我不知道你在做什么。
Harold? I don't know what you think you're doin'.
莉兹，失陪一下。你好。
Liz, excuse me. Hello.
你的箱子里有个白人尸体。
You got a dead white man in a box.
连棺材都没有。
Not even a casket.
重要人物，躺在老木头做的松盒子里。
Important man, in a pine box of old wood.
甚至连车顶都没有。
Doesn't even have a top on it.
他的女儿在哭。
His daughter's cryin'.
你觉得谁会惹上麻烦?
Who do you think is gonna get in trouble here?
-那个黑人，就是他。——弥尔顿。
- The Black man, that's who. - Milton.
现在我们得把他，我们的领袖，我们团的创始人，送进卡车。
Right now we need to get him, our leader, who founded our regiment, into the truck.
做尸检。
Do the autopsy.
之后马上到敏特餐厅见我。
Meet me at Minters Restaurant immediately after.
-知道了。-我需要知道。
- Got it. - I need to know.
我要知道你找到了什么。
I need to know what you found.
好的。
Okay.
- Minters餐厅5点见——弥尔顿。弥尔顿。
- Minters Restaurant at 5:00. - Milton. Milton.
请小心。
Please be careful.
它的轮子坏了。
It's got a bum wheel.
-那可不小心。——弥尔顿。
- That's not careful. - Milton.
所以你永远别想开我的车。
This is why you'll never drive my car.
防腐师会来取这个。
The embalmer is coming for this.
你最好在这里。两个小时。
You better be here. Two hours.
你还记得伯特吧?
You remember Burt, don't you?
-当然。-厄玛·圣克莱尔。
- Of course. - Irma St. Clair.
-你好，伯特。-你好，厄玛。
- Hello, Burt. - Hello, Irma.
不要紧张。
Don't be nervous.
我一个月至少做两次尸检。
I do at least two autopsies a month.
我这辈子做过两次尸检。
I've done two autopsies my whole life.
一个是为了证明我没有在某人的小肠上留下夹子，另一个是为了取下我留在某人小肠上的夹子。
One to prove I didn't leave a clamp on someone's small intestine, the other to remove a clamp I did leave on someone's small intestine.
现在我们知道你对小肠子很在行，伯特。
Now we know you're good with small intestines, Burt.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
你和伯特应该找个时间喝杯咖啡，厄玛。
You know, you and Burt should get coffee sometimes, Irma.
也许你和厄玛应该找个时间喝杯咖啡。
Maybe you and Irma should get coffee sometime.
我们是朋友，米尔顿。
We're friends, Milton.
你知道吗，厄玛，他妻子在家人面前都不替他说话。
You know, Irma, his wife wouldn't stand up for him to her family.
他们已经一年多没住在一起了。
They haven't lived together in over a year.
这就是我的情况。不是现在。
That is my situation. Not now.
我只想看到你快乐。
I just wanna see you happy.
死人会让你意识到时间是短暂的，而爱是真实的，如果你知道它是什么的话。
Dead man makes you realize time is short and love is real, if you know what it is.
-这是怎么回事?——解剖。文书工作。
- What's going on here? - Autopsy. Paperwork.
警察正等着尸体运回停尸间。
The police are waiting for this body to return to the mortuary.
我们越早开始，他就越早出来。
The sooner we start, the sooner he's out.
这两个人必须马上离开。
These two men need to leave immediately.
他们是退伍军人。他们为国家服务。
They're veterans. They served their country.
去麦基餐厅等着。
Go wait at McGee's.
我们会在楼下麦基餐厅。
We'll be downstairs at McGee's.
麦基的。
At McGee's.
厄玛的葡萄牙语。这是不同的。
Irma's Portuguese. That's different.
我不知道你是葡萄牙人。
I didn't know you were Portuguese.
我不是。
I'm not.
你先来还是我先来?
Do you wanna start this or shall I?
只是有点激动，因为我认识他。
Uh, just emotional because I knew him.
如果你愿意，你可以签了这个。
You can just sign this if you want.
不不不不不。
No, no, no, no, no.
-这正是哈罗德需要的——我……我可以帮忙。
- That's what Harold needs. - I... I can help.
他是一个如此善良的人。
He was such a kind man.
好了。
There we go.
哦,上帝。
Oh, God.
毫米。
Mm.
没问你过得怎么样。
Um, didn't ask how you were doing.
我的人走了。
My man left.
这种事每天都在发生。
This kind of thing happens every day.
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
它很好。
It's fine.
真爱是基于选择，而不是需求。
True love is based on choice, not need.
你需要你的妻子还是选择你的妻子?
Do you need your wife or do you choose your wife?
嗯，不能都是吗?
Well, can't it be both?
不。第二个才是真正重要的。
No. The second one is the one that truly matters.
在一天结束的时候，它是。
At the end of the day, it is.
选择比需求更重要。
Choice matters over need.
我不喜欢一个人。
I don't like to be alone.
啊。
Ah.
这听起来像是“需要”。
That sounds like "need."
我要切开它的胃。看那个。
I'm opening up the stomach. Look at that.
哦,是的。那是一种不同寻常的颜色。
Oh, yeah. That's an unusual color.
——……-是的。
- Something... - Yeah.
在一段时间内给他。
Given to him over a period of time.
——嗯。-很难说多久。
- Hmm. - It's hard to tell how long.
嗯。
Hmm.
他刚从欧洲回来。
He just got back from Europe.
我给他缝合，再取些血样。
I'll close him up and take more blood samples.
明天我会告诉你更多的消息。
I'll have more news for you tomorrow.
我想你还在原来的办公室吧?
I take it you're still at the same office?
是的。
Yeah.
哈罗德说你应该过上更好的生活，但你却放任自己堕落。
Harold says you deserve a better circumstance, but you allowed yourself to be corrupted.
他说你跟着错误的上帝回家了。
He says you followed the wrong God home.
什么?“腐败”?
What? "Corrupted"?
"跟随错误的上帝回家"?他怎么不跟我说?
"Followed the wrong God home"? Why doesn't he say that to me?
-这是什么意思?-我不知道。
- What does that even mean? - I don't know.
也许你花了热情和急迫，却不知道自己在浪费，直到为时已晚。
Maybe you spent enthusiasms and urgencies you didn't know you were wasting until it was too late.
当音乐结束的时候，你没有椅子，即使是在你自己的家里。
You ended up without a chair by the time the music ends, even in your own home.
我们需要这个房间。
We need this room.
太好了，我们都要走了。
That's perfect, 'cause we were just leaving.
莉兹说五点后在敏特见。
Liz said to meet her after 5:00 at Minters.
正确的。但我想和你谈谈厄玛。
Right. But I wanna talk to you about Irma.
我这么做的原因，伯特，是因为我想看到你幸福。
Oh, the reason I pushed that, Burt, is because I wanna see you happy.
我是你的朋友。
And I'm your friend.
我的朋友认为我被腐化了，却没有勇气和礼貌当面告诉我。
My friend who thinks I'm corrupted somehow, yet doesn't have the guts or decency to tell it to my face.
你不会想当面听的。
You don't wanna hear that to your face.
你给不让你住在自己公寓里的妻子买了花。
You've got flowers for your wife who won't let you live in your own apartment.
解释“败坏”一词的含义
Explain the word "corrupted"
或者“跟随错误的上帝回家”。
or the term "following the wrong God home."
是你公婆打来的，伯特。
It's your in-laws, Burt.
他们讨厌我们一起工作，更别说我们是朋友了。
They hate that we work together, let alone that we're friends.
我才不听他们说的那些公园大道废话。
Well, I don't listen to any of that Park Avenue garbage from them.
是的，你有。你有那么一点在乎。
Yes, you do. You care a little bit.
只需要一点点，伯特。
And all it takes is a little bit, Burt.
然后他们抓住了你。
Then they got you.
就像我捅那个德国人之前你在战争中留下的那滴血。
Like that drop of blood from the cut you got from the war before I stabbed that German.
那些伤口模糊了你的眼睛，你猜怎么着，你永远失去了这只眼睛。
Those cuts clouded your eye, and guess what, you lost the eye forever.
欢迎来到敏特，先生们。两人桌吗?
Welcome to Minters, gentlemen. Table for two?
我们要去见一个人…——嗯。-一个高个子女人，金发…——是的。——严肃的表情。
Uh, we're actually meeting someone... - Uh-huh. - a tall woman, blonde... - Yes. - serious face.
是的。这边请。
Yes. Right this way.
等待。她来过这里。我不知道发生了什么。
Wait. She was here. I don't know what happened.
她是…在这里。
She was... Right here.
-米金斯小姐。-她来了，伙计
- Miss Meekins. - There she goes, pal.
小姐……等待。Meekins小姐。
Miss... Wait. Miss Meekins.
Meekins小姐。Meekins小姐。
Miss Meekins. Miss Meekins.
我们照你说的做了。
We did what you asked.
我们发现了可疑的东西，和你想的一样。
We found something suspicious, just like you thought.
我做不到。我很抱歉。
I can't do it. I'm sorry.
什么……我和一个私人朋友谈过，他是……Voze先生。
What... I spoke to a personal friend, Mr... Mr. Voze.
他说我必须小心。
He said I have to be careful.
——谁?他吓到你了吗?-他说那很危险。
- Who? Did he scare you? - He said it was dangerous.
等待。米金斯小姐，等一下。
Wait. Miss Meekins, wait a second.
我只需要放下它。
I just need to drop it.
离开这条街。来吧。
Come off the street. Come on.
-你认识我父亲。-是的，是的。
- You knew my father. - Yes, yes.
-你认识我父亲。-是的。
- And you knew my father. - We did.
我们爱你的父亲。是的。
We loved your father. Yes.
你知道他常说什么吗，他常说你无法逃避恐惧。
And you know what he used to say is, he used to say you can't run from fear.
你不能让恐惧围着你转。
You can't let fear chase you around.
我知道我看起来很害怕，我不应该害怕因为沃兹先生，他只是在提醒我。
I know that I seem afraid, and I shouldn't be because Mr. Voze, he was just cautioning me.
他不是……他是好意。
He wasn't... He meant well.
他是我们家的朋友。
He's a friend of the family.
你发现了什么?
What did you find?
我们认为他可能被下毒了。
We believe that he might have been poisoned.
你知道为什么吗?
Do you know why?
有人在监视我吗?我不能……没关系。它……我不知道我能不能谈这个。
Is somebody watching me? I can't... It's okay. It... I don't know if I can talk about this.
结盟对他们有好处，他知道这一点。
They have interests in an alliance, and he knew that.
但他不会同意的。
But he wasn't gonna go along with it.
他知道些什么。他看到了可怕的东西。
He knew something. He saw something terrible.
他做到了。
He did.
他们知道他会说出去。
And they knew he was gonna tell.
告诉什么?他看到了什么?
Tell what? What did he see?
这是危险的。
It's dangerous.
我认为……Meekins小姐!
I think that... Miss Meekins!
我的天啊!Meekins小姐!
Oh, my God! Miss Meekins!
这两个，他们做到了。在这里。
These two, they did it. Right there.
-米金斯小姐!-她死了。
- Miss Meekins! - She's dead.
——噢!-他们做到了。
- Ow! - They did it.
-就在那儿。-你在撒谎!
- Right there. - You're lying!
这两个。他们所做的。
These two right there. They did.
这两个家伙。在这里。
These two guys. Right there.
不!你做到了!你推了她!
No! You did it! You pushed her!
-他们杀了那个女人-我看见你推她了!
- They killed that woman. - I saw you push her!
-他们杀了她!-我看见你了，先生!
- They killed her! - I saw you, sir!
-他们做到了。-我看到了。
- They did it. - I saw it.
我是律师。这是一位医生。
I'm an attorney. This is a doctor.
他们两个。我看见他们干的。
Them two. I saw 'em do it.
她雇了我们。这是我们的客户。
She hired us. This is our client.
看他手里拿的是什么。
Look what he's got in his hand.
-他拿了她的钱包!-他拿了她的钱包。
- He's got her purse! - He's got her purse.
你杀了她，还拿走了她的钱包!
You killed her and took her purse!
不。我看见你了。你推了她。
No. I saw you. You pushed her.
我是个律师……不，不，不!他的……下车!
I'm an attorney... No, no, no! He's... Get off!
公民逮捕!公民逮捕!
Citizen's arrest! Citizen's arrest!
我们要逮捕一个公民!
We'll make a citizen's arrest!
射他们!
Shoot 'em!
让他们!那两个，就在那儿!
Get them! Those two, right there!
停!
Stop!
懦夫!
Cowards!
那个可怜的女孩。哦,上帝。
That poor girl. Oh, God.
来吧。我们走吧。
Come on. Let's go.
在那些车后面!
Behind those cars!
-就是他。-你不能开车。
- That's the man. - You're not driving.
我开车。我们谈过了。
I'm driving. We talked about this.
-就是他。-保持条理。
- That's him. - Stay organized.
我们是一个组织。保持组织。
We're an organization. Stay organized.
他们逃不掉的。
They won't get away.
我们会在这里留意他们的。
We'll keep an eye out for 'em right here.
他们是怎么跟踪我们到这里的?
How the hell did they follow us over here?
加油！加油
Come on, come on.
天啊，这个支架。
God, this brace.
嘿,嘿!
Hey, hey!
嘿!
Hey!
我觉得他们还在监视我们。
I think they're still watching us.
你认为呢?
You think?
我想是的。
I think so.
天呐这是什么鬼东西?
Holy shit. What fresh hell is this?
如果不是很久以前的事，你是不可能来到这里的。
You don't get here without things starting a long time ago.
你想让我去我们最喜欢的树那儿……
You want me to go to our favorite tree...
在阿贡森林里把人炸飞
and get bark in the Argonne Forest where they are blowing people up?
这将是光荣的，光荣的。
It will be honorable, glorious.
对家庭有好处。
Good for the family.
但它……很好，伯特。很好。
But it... it's good, Burt. It's good.
当你获得更多的奖牌时，你会更适应这里。
You'll fit in better when you have more medals.
你会和公园大道很合得来的。
You'll fit in on Park Avenue.
人们尊重服兵役。
People respect military service.
我可能会被杀死。
I could be killed.
我们不能那样想。
We cannot think that way.
你当然不会被杀。
Of course you won't be killed.
啊,比阿特丽斯。
Ah, Beatrice.
我大老远跑到这儿来可不是为了像条狗一样被人唠嗑的。
I didn't come all the way over here to be talked to like a damn dog.
这是违反国旗的罪行。
It's a crime against the flag.
我不认为他们有能力拥有对制服的钦佩和信心。
I don't think they have the ability to possess the admiration or the confidence to wear the uniform.
我们在说谁?
Who are we talking about?
有谁敢挡我的路，我就从背后开枪。
One of these crackers get in my way, I'mma shoot 'em in the back.
我们知道你更喜欢这个。
Well, we know you even like this even more.
我不想再和你说话了。
I was done talking to you.
你永远都不会放过我的。
You'll never be done talking to me.
够了，中士。
That's enough, Sergeant.
是的，长官，米金斯将军。
Yes, sir, General Meekins.
你不用再掺和进来了。
You don't need to be involved anymore.
态度是没用的。
Attitude doesn't help.
所以我才想让你来当医官，伯恩斯坦。
That's why I wanted to bring you on as a medical officer, Bernstein.
Berendsen,先生。
Berendsen, sir.
我很抱歉。我是伍德曼先生。
I'm sorry. This is Mr. Woodman.
这里出了点状况，我想你也许能帮上忙。
Got a situation here that I thought you might be able to help with.
什么情况，先生?
What situation, sir?
伍德曼先生，你为什么不告诉他你为什么在寨子里。
Mr. Woodman, why don't you tell him why you're here in the stockade.
我们为什么在寨子里?
Why are we in a stockade?
不服从。
Insubordination.
你不听话吗?
Were you insubordinate?
——是的。——为什么?
- Yes. - Why?
他们给了我们像那个白痴一样的黑人警察。
They gave us Jim Crow officers like that knucklehead.
但我们拒绝继续，除非他们找到合适的人代替他。
But we refuse to continue till they've replaced him with somebody good.
找个体面又尊重人的人。
Someone decent and respectful.
那是我吗，长官?
Is that supposed to be me, sir?
那就是你，伯伦森。
That is you, Berendsen.
我的意思是，你在这种巨大压力下遇到的人与你的生活息息相关。
I mean, the people you meet in these circumstances of tremendous stress are bonded to you for life.
你是那种会让我失血过多然后我不得不从背后开枪的医生吗?
Are you the kind of doctor that's gonna leave me bleeding out and I'll have to shoot in the back?
因为让我告诉你，他们手下的警官，他们不在乎我们的死活。
Because let me tell you, the officers that they had, they didn't care whether we lived or died.
我不会让任何人失血过多而死，我也不想背后挨一枪。
I am not gonna let anybody bleed out, and I do not wanna get shot in the back.
我是埃尔米拉一个机械师的儿子。
I am the son of a mechanic from Elmira.
我结婚了。
I am married.
我一半是天主教徒，一半是犹太人。
I'm half Catholic, half Jewish.
我是医生。我在公园大道有个诊所。
I'm a doctor. I have a practice on Park Avenue.
我觉得我的公婆派我来是为了赶我走。
And I think that my in-laws sent me here to get rid of me.
听起来不错，除了…姻亲的关系，但也许这就是我可以信任你的原因。
Well, that all sounds pretty good, except that... in-laws part, but maybe that's why I can trust you.
所以，我们要做个约定。
So, we'll make a pact.
你要确保我们不会死。
You see to it that we won't die.
我保证你不会被杀。
And I'll make sure you won't get killed.
我们会互相照顾的。
We'll look out for each other.
哈罗德·塞迪斯·伍德曼。
Harold Thaddeus Woodman.
伯特伦Berendsen。
Bertram Berendsen.
-欢迎来到369。-谢谢。
- Welcome to the 369. - Thank you.
这就是我一直在寻找的。
Finally, that's what I've been looking for.
只是尊重一下。
Just some respect.
现在我们去解决这个不幸的制服问题吧。
Now let's go deal with this unfortunate uniform situation.
是啊，我们去处理制服的事吧。
Yeah, let's go deal with this uniform shit.
欢迎加入我的军队。
Welcome to my army.
我们为什么要穿法国制服?
Why are we wearing French uniforms?
美国士兵，他们不想被看到和我们在一起。
The American soldiers, they don't wanna be seen with us.
这是可耻的。我以善良和团结的精神奋斗创建了这个团。
It's disgraceful. I fought to create this regiment in the spirit of kindness and unity.
希望在阿贡河的另一边见到你。
Hope to see you on the other side of the Argonne in good shape.
愿上帝与你同在。
God be with you.
我救了哈罗德。
I saved Harold.
他救了我。
He saved me.
有个法国女人救了我们俩。
And there was this French lady saving both of us.
把剩下的给我……不要把它扔掉。
Give me the rest... Do not throw that away.
你为什么要留着它?
Why do you want to keep it?
这是不卫生的。
It's unsanitary.
这不关你的事。
It's none of your business.
Et vous ne portez pas de bonnet en plus!
——评论?- Vous ne portez pas de bonnet!
- Comment? - Vous ne portez pas de bonnet!
滚出去!
Get out of here!
滚出去。
Get out of here.
哦啦啦!
Oh la la!
Croyez-moi。
Croyez-moi.
停止这种暴行!
Stop this atrocity!
不雅…犯罪……你是在亵渎……留着这该死的金属!
It's indecent... criminal... and you are blaspheming... by keeping this bloody metal!
-她在亵渎神明?——是的。
- She's blaspheming? - Oui.
我亵渎?
I'm blaspheming?
是的。
Oui.
那金属进去的时候很恶心。
The metal was obscene when it went in.
我把它取出来的时候再兑换。
I redeem it when I take it out.
你宁愿把一切都隐藏起来。
You prefer to keep it all hidden.
它侮辱了上帝……还有死者和伤者的家属。
It insults God... and the families of the dead and the wounded.
不，她说得对。
No, she's right.
谢谢。
Merci.
她可以留着这该死的金属。
She can keep this bloody metal.
——什么?——谢谢。
- Quoi? - Merci.
是的，是的，是的。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-她说得对。-看到了吗?
- She's right. - You see?
- Vous voyez!好了。——好。
- Vous voyez! Allez. - Allez.
世界万岁!世界万岁!
Tout le monde! Tout le monde!
杜calme !杜calme !
Du calme! Du calme!
放轻松，哈罗德。
Take it easy, Harold.
这是有理由的!你们看到!
Il a raison! Vous voyez!
你们看到!好了。好了。
Vous voyez! Allez. Allez.
你好大的胆子!
How dare you!
我的天啊!
Oh, my God!
Ca suffit。
Ça suffit.
我不知道发生了什么事。
I don't know what is happening.
Liberté pour nous tous。Arrêtez de mentir!
Liberté pour nous tous. Arrêtez de mentir!
“自由……
Liberté...
伍德曼先生，我想我应该感谢你。
Mr. Woodman, I believe I owe you my gratitude.
哦，你会说英语?
Oh, you speak English?
——是的。-我以为你是法国人。
- Yes. - I thought you were French.
我是瓦莱丽·班登伯格。
I'm Valerie Bandenberg.
-你不是法国人?——没有。
- You're not French? - No.
我可以请你喝一杯吗?
May I buy you a drink?
是的。我们……我们可以在这里做吗?
Yes. We... We can do that here?
-我可以。-我们可以…我们可以在这里喝酒吗?
- I can. - We can... We can drink here?
哈罗德!
Harold!
-你到底在干什么?-年轻人!
- What the hell are you doing? - Young man!
你要去哪里?
Where you goin'?
他和我在一起很安全。
Oh, he's in safe hands with me.
如果那些密西西比的家伙现在能看到你…协议怎么了?
If those Mississippi crackers could see you now... What happened to the pact?
我在这里失去了一只眼睛。
I lost an eye here.
抽烟斗的女人抽烟斗的女人
A woman who smokes a pipe.
你害怕吗?
Are you intimidated?
现在有一点。
A little bit right now.
当你看到一个人，你真的看到了他们，你看到的是曾经的他们。
When you see someone, and you really see them, you see the kid that used to be them.
你看到了他们脆弱的一面。
You see the part of them that's vulnerable.
哈罗德和我从一开始就有这种感觉。
Harold and I had that kind of seeing each other right from the start.
既然战争已经结束了…
Well, now that the war is over...
我只想做一个真正的人。你知道吗?
I just want to be a person. You know?
我只想自由自在地四处走走……毫米。
I just want to walk around - free... - Mm.
作为一个人。只是…过我自己的生活。
As a person. Just... Just living my life.
这里是欧洲。
Here in Europe.
这就是问题所在。活下去，自由自在。
That's the ticket. Just live and be free.
我强烈推荐它。我已经走遍了欧洲。
I highly recommend it. I've walked around Europe.
它给我带来了奇迹。
It's done wonders for me.
不用多说，她就能看穿你的灵魂。
Without even too many words, I mean, she's looking right into your soul.
是啊，你穿得很好。
Yeah, you wear it well.
我们的生命在上帝面前岌岌可危。在这里。
Both our lives were in the balance before God. Right there.
我能问你个问题吗?
Can I ask you something?
毫米。
Mm.
你怎么处理从我们身上取出的血淋淋的弹片?
What do you do with the bloody shrapnel that you take from our bodies?
我不能白给你。
I can't give you that for nothing.
你得跟我换一样东西。
You have to trade me something.
这不是免费的。
You don't get that for free.
贸易吗?
Trade you?
好的。多少钱?
Okay. What does it cost?
美丽的东西。
Something beautiful.
活着的意义。
Something to live for.
我现在正看着呢。
I'm looking at that right now.
我已经把我身上的金属弹片给你了。
I already gave you pieces of metal shrapnel from my body.
其实，我从你朋友的身体里提取了更多的金属。
You know, actually, I took a lot more metal from your friend's body.
他叫什么名字?
What's his name?
他叫伯特·伯伦森。
His name is Burt Berendsen.
哦,男孩。
Oh, boy.
他一瘸一拐地走着，想起了一段友谊的约定。
And he is hobbling along here, remembering something about a friendship pact.
你还记得吗?还记得我吗?我在这里。
Do you remember that? Remember me? Here I am.
-很高兴见到你，伯特- - - - - -你好。
- Good to see you, Burt. - Hello.
对不起，伯特·伯伦森。
My apologies, Burt Berendsen.
我倒两杯的时候再也不会少了第三杯了。
Never again shall I pour two without a third.
伯特，你得帮帮我…-很好。-用美好的东西交换，作为回报，她会向我们展示她如何处理她从我们身体上取下的金属。
Hey, Burt, you gotta help me... - Very good. - trade something beautiful, and in return, she's gonna show us what she does with all the metal she took from our bodies.
她叫瓦莱丽。
Her name is Valerie.
你怎么处理那些弹片，瓦莱丽?
What do you do with all that shrapnel, Valerie?
如果你想知道，你得跟我换一样东西。
If you want to know, you have to trade me something.
-她也是这么说的。-我什么都没有。
- She told me the same thing. - I got nothing.
无意义的歌。
Nonsense song.
这是个好主意。怎么样?
That's a good idea. How about that?
什么是废话歌?
What's a nonsense song?
好吧。
All right.
红色的太阳。
The red sun.
嗯…一些柚子。
Um... Some grapefruit.
他的手帕。
The handkerchief.
红日……一些柚子…手帕……当你打电话的时候。
The red sun... some grapefruit... the handkerchief... when you call.
看到一张脸…谁的?
To see a face... whose?
我的名字……我自己的名字。
My name... my own name.
它是生动的，那一刻……去爱，才会存在。
It's vivid, the moment... to love, to be.
你说对了。
You got it.
海滩很温暖……天空很冷……死亡是真实的…当我们奄奄一息的时候。
The beach is warm... The sky is cold... Death is real... when we're dying.
但是天空……有了朋友是温暖的。
But the sky... is warm with friends.
我从人的身体里取出过这些东西。
I've taken all these pieces out of people's bodies.
看。这个东西更原始。
Look. This is more primitive, this stuff.
看，我要开一个茶话会。
Look, I'm having a tea party.
这是用火药做的。和弹片。
This is made out of gun powder. And shrapnel.
文明的高度。
The height of civilization.
欢迎来到我的世界。
Welcome to my world.
哦，我在化妆。
Oh, I'm doing my makeup.
我只有半张脸吗?
Oh, do I only have half a face?
这是怎么发生的?
How did that happen?
只要我有口红就行。
As long as I have my lipstick.
漂亮。
Pretty.
你得知道你喜欢什么。
You got to know what you love.
你得从生活中得到真正的乐趣，否则，如果你任其发展，会有太多该死的麻烦从头到尾地破坏这种生活的乐趣。
And you got to get a real kick out of it, or there's too much damn trouble in it to spoil this affair of living from beginning to end, if you let it.
为什么不为美好的事物而活，即使你有点穷?
Why not live it for the beautiful things, even if you were a bit broke?
我的比阿特丽斯会怎么想我眼睛不见了的事，还有我背上的伤疤，还有所有的一切?
What will my Beatrice think about the missing eye business, and the scars, and the scars on my back and everything?
我们能做点什么吗，瓦莱丽?
Can we do anything about that, Valerie?
我认识阿姆斯特丹一家医院的捐助者。
I know benefactors in a hospital in Amsterdam.
它们会给你一个新的眼睛。
They'll give you a new eye.
阿姆斯特丹吗?
Amsterdam?
几年前我刚去法国的时候，情况要困难一些。
When I was first going through France a couple of years ago, okay, things were a little more difficult.
我不得不捅了一个人。
I had to stab a guy.
有一次我拿砖头砸了一位女士。
I had to hit a lady with a brick one time.
什么?
What?
——哇。-是啊，说来话长
- Wow. - Yeah, it's a long story.
但有你俩，就小菜一碟了。
But with you two, it will be a cakewalk.
再说了，我现在伪造文件的技术好多了。
And besides, I'm far better at forging documents now.
来吧，伯特。我们去阿姆斯特丹吧。
Come on, Burt. Let's go to Amsterdam.
好的。
Okay.
-谢谢我frères。——勇气!
- Merci mes frères. - Courage!
我是阿姆斯特丹的移交官。
Nous avons I'ordre officiel de transfert pour Amsterdam.
看了ca。谢谢。
Regarde ça. Merci.
-谢谢，夫人。- Mais attendez!
- Merci Madame. - Mais attendez!
Mais qu'est-ce que vous faites?
但是…但是…各位先生美女…但是…你们rigolez ?
Mais... Mais... Messieurs dames... Mais... vous rigolez?
是的，是的，夫人。这是très重要的。
Oui, oui Madame. C'est très important.
Mais Madame remettez les clés。
Mais Madame remettez les clés.
谢谢。
Merci.
-你好，我的朋友们。——啊!
- Bonjour mes amis. - Ah!
-你好。-你好。弗吉尼亚州吗?
- Bonjour. - Bonjour. Ça va?
——Mwah。Ça va. -你在这。
- Mwah. Ça va. - There you are.
保罗·坎特伯雷。坎特伯雷玻璃。
Paul Canterbury. Canterbury Glass.
伦敦,英格兰。
London, England.
我们制造最好的假体玻璃，工业玻璃，绝密玻璃，军事玻璃，除了窗户玻璃，所有的玻璃…当然，除非它是防弹的。
We make the finest prosthetic glass, industrial glass, top-secret glass, military glass, every kind of glass except window glass... Unless, of course, it's bulletproof.
不要害怕。瓦莱丽小姐的朋友是保罗·坎特伯雷的朋友，他会为你提供终生的坎特伯雷玻璃眼睛。
Have no fear. A friend of Miss Valerie is a friend of Paul Canterbury, who offers you a lifetime supply of Canterbury glass eyes.
还不错。
Not too bad.
如你所见，我也受了同样的伤。
As you can see, I've got the same injury as you.
或者你看不见是因为坎特伯雷玻璃的精细工艺。
Or perhaps you can't see due to the fine craftsmanship of Canterbury Glass.
让我看看。我相信你是一个……是的，深褐色的。我说的对吗，先生?
Let me see. I believe you are a... Yes, a dark hazel-green. Am I correct, sir?
你是正确的。
You're correct.
万岁。这是我的美国同事，亨利·诺克罗斯。
Huzzah. This is my American colleague, Henry Norcross.
你好!多年来我们一直是瓦莱丽家族的国际生意朋友。
How do you do? We've been friends of Valerie's family through international business for many years.
我们在她的冒险之旅中保护了她的安全，作为回报，她也为造福世界做出了贡献。
We've kept her safe on her adventure, and in return, she's helped serve the good of the world.
她到底是怎么做到的?
How did she do that exactly?
通过参加各种晚宴和活动，告诉我们她对银行和军队调动的了解，等等。
By attending various dinners and functions, and telling us what she's learned about banks and troop movement, so on and so forth.
啊哈。你是间谍。
Uh-huh. You're spies.
不。没有,先生。
No. No, sir.
他在一家玻璃公司工作，而我在财政部工作。
He, uh, works for a glass company, and I work for the Department of the Treasury.
他们是老朋友了。
They're old friends.
他们帮过我，我也帮过他们。
They've helped me out, and I've helped them out.
现在我想他们会帮你的。
Now I think they'll help you out.
就连保罗和我也抽出时间来这里观鸟。
Even Paul and I have found some time to do a little birding here.
我们是狂热的观鸟者。
We're avid birders.
是的。这真的是一种精妙的爱好。
Yes. It's an exquisite hobby, really.
是的。
Yes.
这是非洲灰冠鹤。
This is, uh, the African gray crowned crane.
是的。
Yep.
它们已经灭绝了。
These are extinct.
是的，我们有后两种。
Yes, we have the last two.
尼克巴，鸽子。
The Nicobar, uh, pigeon.
是的。
Yes.
他们一度还活着。
They were alive at one point.
这是北美野鸡。
And this is the North American pheasant.
这是一只北美野鸡，我喜欢称它为野鸡中的农民。
It's a North American pheasant, which I like to call the peasant of pheasants.
你看，它们太常见了。
They're so common, you see.
-但是它们很漂亮。——是的。
- But they are beautiful. - Yes.
它的羽毛真漂亮。
The plumage is really outstanding.
所以，你知道，我们很乐意为你的脸付钱，不管你需要什么整容治疗，嗯……顶级的，最好的。
So, you know, we're happy to pay for the faces, whatever cosmetic healing you might need, uh... Top-shelf, nothing but the best.
是的,是的。还有阿姆斯特丹的美好生活，在经历了这一切之后你应该在这里休息和自由。
Yes, yes. As well as a good life here in Amsterdam, where you deserve a rest and some freedom after what you've been through.
将来我们需要你们这些好人帮忙的时候，我们会来找你们的。
We'll come a-calling sometime in the future when we need you good people to help us out.
是的。
Yes.
因为总有一天我们会对这些制造这场我们无法理解的战争的疯子说“够了”。
Because there will come a time to say "enough" to these madmen who create this war we cannot make any sense of.
这怪物怎么可能再出现呢?
Well, how could this monstrosity repeat itself?
这应该是一场结束所有战争的战争。
It's supposed to be the war to end all wars.
正确的。
Right.
因为梦会重复，因为它会忘记自己。
Because the dream repeats itself since it forgets itself.
这就是为什么它会重复。
That's why it repeats itself.
这是好的部分。
This is the good part.
但不好的部分总有一天会再次出现。
But the bad part will come again one day.
但现在，这是阿姆斯特丹的好地方。
But for now, this is the good part, in Amsterdam.
这些是灯。
These are the lights right here.
它们可能有点棘手。
They can be a little tricky.
你得向上，向下，向上，向下，向上。
You gotta go up, down, up, down, up.
它们会闪烁一会儿。看到了吗?
They'll flicker for a little bit. See?
卢米埃。
Lumière.
我是说，这地方很大。
I mean, it's a big place.
保罗和亨利帮我安排的，但太乱了。
Paul and Henry organized it for me, but it's a wreck.
她是对的。
She was right.
-这是精彩的部分。-还有这个水龙头…-太棒了。-我是说，别被吓到。当你用水的时候……它会这样做的。
- This was the good part. - And this tap... - It was fantastic. - I mean, don't let it scare you. When you use the water... it will do that.
整个世界突然变成了我们的牡蛎，它是如此的辉煌。
The world was suddenly our oyster and it was glorious.
这是正常的。
That's normal.
是的。阿姆斯特丹是在心脏，一直在那里。
Yeah. Amsterdam is in the heart, and was there all along.
去吧!
Go on!
保罗，让他们看看沙舞!
Paul, show them the sand dance!
沙舞。
The sand dance.
疯狂的大英帝国沙舞。
The crazy British Empire sand dance.
她聪明又疯狂。
She was brilliant and nuts.
但她和我们是一类疯子。
But she was our kind of nuts.
所以条约现在有了三个。
And so the pact now had three.
我在阿姆斯特丹呆了一段时间，因为那里的景色很美。
I stayed in Amsterdam for a while because it was glorious there.
他又稳又壮。
He was steady and strong.
她很大胆，很聪明。
She was bold and luminous.
这就是法国人所说的“千钧一发”。
It was what the French call a coup de foudre.
一见钟情。
Love at first sight.
她创造了自己的艺术。
She made her art.
我是他们最好的朋友，用我的新眼睛。
I was their best friend, with my new eye.
我们帮助经过城镇的老兵。——好的。这工作。
We helped vets - passing through town. - Okay. That works.
我们经常去跳舞。
We went dancing all the time.
它是宏伟的。
It was magnificent.
在探戈舞厅，你真的会觉得自己在飞翔。
These tango parlors, you really feel like you're flying.
你不能走。我…那边现在太糟糕了。
You can't go. I... It's terrible over there right now.
-你在说什么?-我要见我妻子。
- What are you talking about? - I have to see my wife.
伯特，我有很不好的预感。
Burt, I have a very bad feeling about this.
我…我认为如果你离开是一个不好的预兆。
I... I think it's a bad omen if you leave.
请不要走。
Please don't go.
我成了公园大道的一名医生。
I became a doctor on Park Avenue.
-公园大道。-我结婚了。
- Park Avenue. - I'm married.
我们可以……我们能算出来的，对吧?我们可以……我对公园大道略知一二。
We can... We can figure it out, right? We can... I know a thing or two about Park Avenue.
请不要走。
Please don't go.
瓦莱丽。
Valerie.
让我们现实一点。这不会永远持续下去。
Let's be realistic. This can't last forever.
我们要怎么生活?
How are we supposed to live?
我想念碧翠丝，尽管她和她的家人把我送去了战场。
I missed Beatrice, even though she and her family sent me off to war.
为你的国家服务。
Serve your country.
我第一次见到她是在医学院的慈善活动上
When I first met her, I was at a charity event at medical school.
我看到了这个女人，我见过的最漂亮的女人。
And I see this woman, the most beautiful woman I've ever seen.
我的天啊。你真该看看她。
Oh, my God. You should've seen her.
我们跳了一整晚。
And we danced all night.
我们都头晕了。我们都笑了。
We were giddy. We were laughing.
我们相爱了。
We were in love.
我不知道她是那个给我奖学金的人的女儿。
I had no idea that she was the daughter of the guy who gave me the scholarship.
在他眼里，这个有一半犹太人血统的人，就像是在说"你可以拿奖学金，但我女儿，- "不准拿"-听起来很糟糕。
In his eyes, this half Jew, he was like, "You can have the scholarship, but my daughter, - "uh-uh, off-limits." - Sounds bad.
你可以选择你的朋友。
You can choose your friends.
你不能选择你的家庭。
You can't choose your family.
我选择了你。这……我有点尴尬了，因为你可能不这么想。
And I choose you. And this... I'm getting embarrassed, because you might not feel the same way.
但这段感情，可能是我生命中最重要的东西。
But this relationship, probably the most important thing in my life.
是的。
Yeah.
我们同意。所以保持。
We do agree. So stay.
但我不能放弃碧翠丝。
But I can't quit Beatrice.
我爱她。
I love her.
当然，他们说你会有奖章。
Sure, they say you'll have medals.
你会和公园大道很合得来的。
You'll fit in on Park Avenue.
这就是我受到的英雄般的欢迎。
Well, this was the hero's welcome I received.
不，我告诉过你，你不能在这里治疗这些病人。
No, I've told you before, you cannot treat these patients here.
这完全不合适。
It's just completely inappropriate.
我之所以认识这些病人是因为你让我上了战场。
The only reason I know these patients is because you made me go to war.
你要明白，这种事不会发生在公园大道上。
You understand, this does not happen on Park Avenue.
而且你服用了太多吗啡。
And you've been taking too much morphine.
你离我女儿远点。
You stay away from my daughter.
你被列入黑名单了。
You are blacklisted.
走了。离开。你必须离开。你必须离开这里。
Go. Leave. You must leave. You must leave here.
不要去公寓。我将……我会给你寄衣服的。
Don't go to the apartment. I'll... I'll send you clothes.
伯特伦,呆!我很抱歉。
Bertram, stay! I'm sorry.
嘿。嘿。嘿，嘿，嘿。
Hey. Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
我怎么能不帮助老兵呢?
How can I not help the veterans?
嘿。
Hey.
我把诊所搬到了大琼斯街的一条小巷里。
I had relocated my practice to an alley off Great Jones Street.
吃止痛药的时候有点失控了。
It got a little out of control with the pain medicine.
我被强制休息，这是纽约州的恩赐。
And I was given an enforced rest, courtesy of the State of New York.
来吧，伙计。
Come on, buddy.
写信给我朋友，让他们救我出来。
Wrote my friends to help get me out.
不知道这会对他们造成什么影响。
Had no idea what it would do to them.
如果你的家人有能力帮伯特出狱，我觉得你应该这么做。
If your family has the kind of influence that can help Burt get out of jail, I think you should do it.
约定就是约定，瓦莱丽。
I mean, the pact is the pact, Valerie.
我告诉过你我逃离了什么，不是吗?
I told you I ran away from something, didn't I?
这就是你需要知道的。
That's all you need to know.
但是，是的，我的家人可能会帮他。
But, yes, my family could possibly help him.
但如果我联系他们，他们就会知道我在哪里。
But if I contact them, they'll know where I am.
如果他们知道我在哪里，他们可能会想办法把我拖回去。
And if they know where I am, they will find a way to possibly drag me back.
他们很有说服力。
And they're very persuasive.
他所做的一切都是为了帮助这个团。
All he was doing was trying to help the regiment.
我听说那些人在老家日子不好过。
I hear those guys have it rough back at home.
我想我们都知道这是怎么回事。
I think we both knew where this was headed anyway.
-是的。-你这是什么意思?
- Yeah. - What do you mean by that?
我是说，我们…我们只存在于阿姆斯特丹。
Well, I mean, we... we only exist in Amsterdam.
你也说了很多关于你回美国后打算做的事。
You know, and you've spoken a lot about the things that you plan on doing back in America.
也许是时候了。
Maybe it's time.
我说我想成为一名律师。
I said I wanted to become a lawyer.
为人民而战。
To fight for people.
人们喜欢家乡的那些士兵。
People like those soldiers back at home.
我想为那些无法反抗的人而战，为那些无法利用法律为自己而战的人而战。
I wanted to fight for people like that who couldn't fight back, who couldn't fight for themselves, to use the law.
你还说你想和我一起住在阿姆斯特丹。
You also said that you wanna live in Amsterdam with me.
是的。
Yes.
我两样都想做。我想回家战斗。
I wanna do both. I wanna go back home and fight.
我想和你待在一起。
And I wanna stay here with you.
我想活下去。我想要真正的生活。
And I wanna live. I wanna truly live.
你怎么能同时拥有这两样东西呢?
How do you have both those things?
有个办法。
There's a way.
但现在我们得帮伯特。
But right now we have to help Burt.
我们会怎么样?我爱你。
What will happen to us? I love you.
我们得帮伯特。
We gotta help Burt.
好的。
Okay.
穿好衣服。
Get dressed.
不久之后的一天，她消失了，除了一张便条，没跟哈罗德说一句话。
She vanished, one day soon after, without a word to Harold, except a note.
我突然从监狱里被释放了。
I was suddenly released from jail.
再也没有她的消息。
Never heard from her.
哈罗德回到了纽约。拿到了法律学位。
Harold came back to New York. Got his law degree.
你有权要求赔偿。
You have a claim.
我们一起工作了10多年。
We worked together over 10 years.
好医生和我会好好照顾你的。
The good doctor and I will take good care of you.
我们帮别人摆脱了各种麻烦，直到米金斯的案子。
All kinds of trouble we got people out of, until the Meekins case.
这就是我们现在所处的困境。
This was trouble that now we were in, ourselves.
我们很可能无法存活。
And we may very well not survive.
我的天啊。那个可怜的女孩。
Oh, my God. That poor girl.
我受不了了。
I can't bear this.
某物出事了，哈罗德。
Something... Something is very wrong, Harold.
你总是对我说的那句话是什么?
What's that thing that you always say to me?
我们会奋战到底的。
We'll fight through it.
不管发生什么，我们都会有办法的。
We'll find a way, no matter what.
谢谢你！我需要这个。
Thank you. I need that.
在那里……你要去哪里?
Where... Where you going?
我们离开这条街会更安全。
It's safer if we can get off the street.
哦……我知道我们在哪里。
Oh... I know where we are.
我知道我们在哪里。不是那个女人，伯特。
I know where we are. Not that woman, Burt.
灯都关了。这是一个惊喜晚餐吗?
The lights are off. Is it a surprise dinner?
她认识莉兹·米金斯那个世界的人。
She knows people from Liz Meekins's world.
这个地方看起来还是老样子。
The place looks the same.
闻起来像樟脑丸，像你的婚姻。
Smells of mothballs, like your marriage.
谢谢你,朋友。
Thanks, pal.
如果没有诚实，朋友还有什么用?
What are friends for if not honesty?
火,会被火灼伤。情况如何?
That burns. How we looking?
好吗?
Good?
帮助我。
Help me.
-是直的吗?-是的。
- Is that straight? - Yeah.
哦，我明白了。
Oh, I see.
你在她面前装得真漂亮啊?
You're really putting it on nice for her, huh?
伯特伦吗?
Bertram?
坐下来。放松。
Sit down. Relax.
伯特，别等太久。
Hey, Burt, don't be too long.
帮我个忙。
Do me a favor.
-试着乐观一点。——伯特伦?伯特伦吗?
- Try to be optimistic. - Bertram? Bertram?
哦，看看你。
Oh, look at you.
没有晚餐。我很抱歉。我很抱歉。这是一个错误。
There is no dinner. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. It was a mistake.
你为什么邀请我?
Why did you invite me?
因为它是…我有一时的软弱。
Because it was... I had a moment of weakness.
我们变成这样了?一时的软弱?
That's what we've become? A moment of weakness?
不能让我父亲知道我在做这件事因为他会剥夺我所有的特权。
And my father can't even know that I'm doing this because he'll take away all kinds of privileges.
怎么了?
What's wrong here?
你还记得我们在晚上，只唱艾米莉·狄金森的诗，一起唱歌，彼此对视吗?
Do you remember when we would have nights, just Emily Dickinson poetry, and singing together and just staring at each other?
-怎么了?-我记得，是的。
- What happened? - I remember, yeah.
这就是为什么我爱你。
That's why I love you.
你摔倒了吗?
Did you fall?
你的背受伤了吗?让我看一下。
Did you hurt your back? Let me take a look at it.
我的背疼了一整天。
My back has been killing me all day.
现在不是时候。
This is not the right time.
只是看了一眼。来吧。
Just a glimpse. Come on.
你曾经如此美丽。
You were once so beautiful.
看在上帝的份上。
Oh, for God's sakes.
而现在你变得又丑又丑。
And now you're just hideous and grotesque.
你又丑又畸形。
You're so ugly and deformed.
看着你真是太难受了。
It's so hard to look at you.
你穿得像个女人。
And you wear a corset like a woman.
-你很无助。-碧翠丝，我受不了了。
- You're helpless. - Beatrice, I can't do this anymore.
你对我的伤疤这么不正常。
This deviance that you've come to have about my scars.
你是选择我，还是需要我?
Do you choose me or do you need me?
这是什么问题啊?
What kind of a question is that?
今天我和一个人聊天，他们说爱是选择一个人，而不是因为其他原因需要他。
I was talking to someone today and they said that love is choosing someone, not needing them for some other reason.
是我们相遇时你需要我，还是你选择了我这个人?
Did you need me when we met, or did you choose me as a person?
是因为我身边的人吗?
Was it the people around me?
你还是从纽约北部来的奖学金生时我家族在医学界的声望?
The prestige of my family in medicine when you were a scholarship student from Upstate New York?
还是你选择了我?
Or did you choose me?
只是我吗?
Just me?
我刚才也问过伯特同样的问题。
I asked Burt the exact same question just a little while ago.
哈罗德樵夫。
Harold Woodman.
你为什么拿着女人的钱包?
Why do you have a woman's purse?
比尔·米金斯的女儿莉兹，今晚被推到了卡车下面。
Bill Meekins's daughter, Liz, was pushed under a truck tonight.
你是认真的吗?
What, are you serious?
她雇我是因为我们和她父亲关系很好。
She hired me because we were close to her father.
所以她才信任我们。
That's why she trusted us.
不知为何，他们认为是我们干的。
Somehow, they think that we did it.
我们需要一个人。我们需要一些东西。
And we need somebody. We need something.
我们需要有人帮助我们。
We need someone to help us.
“罗斯”这个名字怎么样?
What about the name "Rose"?
这是莉斯·米金斯死前说的最后一句话，罗斯先生能帮她。
That's the last thing Liz Meekins said before she died, that a Mr. Rose could help her.
莉兹绝不会认识一个叫罗斯的人。那是犹太人的名字。
Liz would never have known a Rose. That's a Jewish name.
哦。谢谢你，碧翠丝。
Oh. Thank you, Beatrice.
你只有一半。哈罗德，你听错了。
You're only half. Harold, you misheard.
为什么?
Why?
因为必须是"Voze"加" v "
Because it has to be "Voze" with a "V."
那是社会记录上有名的家族。
That's a prominent family in the Social Register.
沃兹一家在最上面。
The Vozes are at the top of it.
伯特，这就是我说的。
Burt, this is what I'm talking about.
我们身处的是你的世界，不是我的。
This is your world that we're in trouble in, not mine.
那是什么?
What's that?
你怎么敢进来?
How dare you come in here?
门没锁。
The door was unlocked.
这还是你登记的地址，对吧?
This is still your listed address, right?
显然如此。
Apparently so.
盖特韦勒警探，什么风把你吹来了?莱姆，你还需要药吗?
Detective Getweiler, what brings you here at this hour? You need more pills, Lem?
我知道你和我戴着一样的支架，不像希尔兹先生。
I know you have the same brace as I do, not like Mr. Hiltz.
你的平拱让德国人在莱茵兰看不到你。
Your flat arches stopped the Germans from seeing you in the Rhineland.
你知道我为什么来这里，伯特。
You know why I'm here, Burt.
你和伍德曼在把米金斯家的女人推到卡车下面后逃离了现场。
You and Woodman fled the scene after you pushed the Meekins woman under a truck.
你为什么会认为是我们干的?
Why would you possibly think that was us?
没有多少人符合医生和他的黑人律师在地上寻找他的眼睛的描述。
Well, there's not too many people that fit the description of a doctor looking for his eye on the ground with his Black attorney.
死去的女人雇了哈罗德调查她父亲的死。
The woman who died hired Harold to look into her father's death.
我今天下午给他做了尸检。
I did an autopsy on him this afternoon.
他是我们所在兵团的将军，莱姆。
He was the general of the regiment we served in, Lem.
目击者说你推了她。
Witnesses say you pushed her.
不，我们必须离开那里。当时一片混乱。
No, we had to get out of there. It was chaos.
一场打斗爆发了。凶手指着我们。
A fight broke out. The killer pointed at us.
他很擅长当罪犯。
He's very good at being a criminal.
我只知道一件事。
Well, I know one thing.
我得给队长一个答案。
I need to give my captain answers.
现在，你们两个是嫌疑人。
And at the moment, you two are the suspects.
你能证明你和莉兹·米金斯有雇佣合同吗?
Can you prove you have an employment contract with Liz Meekins?
她雇你做她的律师吗?
That she hired you to be her attorney?
绝对的。我可以拿给你。
Absolutely. I can get that to you.
另外，我可以给你初步尸检报告和比尔·米金斯的遗产文件。
Plus, I can get you the preliminary autopsy report and the Bill Meekins estate papers.
好。
Good.
不，我们得…我们得带你去…-别碰我。——Hiltz。Hiltz Hiltz。
No, we gotta... we gotta take you in... - Get your hands off of me. - Hiltz. Hiltz, Hiltz.
我是律师协会的一员。
I'm a part of the Bar Association.
别碰我。
Don't touch me.
我甚至不喜欢这个人是律师。
I don't even like that this man is a lawyer.
哥伦比亚大学法学院。
Columbia Law School.
也许你的平臀弓让你很难理解。
Maybe those flat-ass arches of yours make that hard for you to comprehend.
别跟我说我的扁足。
Don't talk to me about my flat arches.
我要敲碎你的头…希尔兹，不，你不会的。别吵了!
I'll crack your head right... Hiltz, no, you won't. Knock it off!
如果我们找个人为我们做担保呢?
What if we got someone to vouch for us?
社会登记处的人吗?
Someone from the Social Register?
这会引起你们队长的注意吗?
Would that get your captain's attention?
像沃兹先生这样认识比尔·米金斯的人。
Someone like Mr. Voze, who knew Bill Meekins.
伯特伦……比阿特丽斯。
Bertram... Beatrice.
我的家人是州医疗委员会的长期成员。
My family are long-standing members of the state medical board.
我可以证明这两个男人都是可怕的骗子，对彼此都是，更不用说对警察了。
And I can attest to the fact that both of these men are horrible liars, to each other, let alone to the police.
如果你在给他们机会给你他们所提供的一切之前就收留了他们，我担心这可能会让你失去工作。
If you take them in before giving them the chance to give you everything that they've offered, I'm afraid it might cost you your job.
我父亲在市政厅有很多朋友。
My father has a lot of friends at City Hall.
把你答应过的东西都给我们。
Get us everything you promised.
明白吗，你和我，我们有共同点。
Understand, you and me, we got something in common.
我们服过役，不像这家伙。
We served, not like this guy.
丢失的钱包怎么办?它去哪了?
What about the missing purse? Where did that go?
这可能……这可能是证据。
This could... This could be evidence.
你拿那个干什么?把它放下。
What are you doing with that? Put that down.
-放回去。-这里面是什么?
- Put that back. - What's in here?
-这是什么?-把它放下。
- What's this? - Put it down.
-我只是说…-放回去。
- I'm just saying... - Put that back.
哦,哦。
Oh-oh.
我很抱歉。我很小心。
I'm sorry. I was being careful.
你怎么了?
What is the matter with you?
他在学习，伯特。
He's learning, Burt.
他,呃…他可以成为一个好侦探。
He, uh... He can be a good detective.
你跟沃兹谈过之后，马上告诉我。
And when you spoke to Voze, you let me know right away.
我不会等那么久的。听到了吗，伯特?
I'm not gonna wait that long. You hear me, Burt?
——是的。-我给你几天时间。
- Yes. - I'll give you a few days.
但如果有必要的话-我会亲自带你来。-我明白。
But if I have to, - I'll bring you in myself. - I understand.
-我还需要一些药。-我知道了。
- And I need some pills too. - I got it.
我很快就会在你办公室见你。
I'll be seeing you in your office pretty soon.
——是的。-但情况很糟糕。
- Yes. - But it's a bad situation.
这很糟糕。
It's very bad.
那真是令人兴奋。
Well, that was exciting.
去拿你的东西，但别在回家的路上被杀了。
Go and get your things, but don't get killed on the way home.
五人委员会，活下去。
Committee of the Five, stay alive.
闭上你的嘴。
Keep your mouth shut.
为什么不直接开车朝我们开枪?
Why not just drive up and shoot us?
五人委员会，永远活着!
Committee of the Five, always alive!
这家伙还想对我们做什么?
What else did this guy have in mind for us?
我们无处不在。
We're everywhere.
所以现在我们必须撒谎才能进入这家伙的房子。
So now we have to lie to get into this guy's house.
怎样做并不重要。我们要去见沃兹先生。
Doesn't matter how. We are gonna see Mr. Voze.
什么是慈善?
What is this charity?
这是圣公会的。
Okay, that's the Episcopal one.
门开了，你说?
The door opens and you say?
我说:“你好……”
I say, "Hello..."
我是伯特·伯伦森医生。
My name is Dr. Burt Berendsen.
这位是哈罗德·伍德曼，时尚先生，荣誉勋章获得者。
This is Harold Woodman, Esquire, Medal of Honor recipient.
这是英勇十字勋章，不是荣誉勋章，你知道的。
It's the Croix de Guerre, not the Medal of Honor, and you know that.
十字勋章，是的。对不起。
Croix de Guerre, yes. Sorry.
我们知道圣公会教徒有多爱沃兹先生。
We know how the Episcopalians love Mr. Voze.
他错过了你会很遗憾的。他不在。
He'll be sorry to have missed you. He's not in.
你觉得他什么时候会回来?
Well, when do you think he'll be back?
我不知道。
I don't know.
但也许你可以把那封信交给我?
But perhaps you could leave that letter with me?
我们得把这个直接交给沃兹先生。
We need to hand this directly to Mr. Voze.
是主教的命令。
On orders from the Bishop.
正确的。那你可以留张卡片。
Right. Well, then, you can leave a card.
很抱歉让你们失望了，先生们。
I'm sorry to disappoint you, gentlemen.
不过，你介意吗?
However, do you mind?
我看着这个柜子，然后我…我忍不住认出了这些工艺品。
I'm looking at this cabinet, and I... I couldn't help but recognize these crafts.
这些是医院制造的吗?
Are these made in a hospital, over here?
看到了吗?是的。
See? Yes.
看起来像是老兵的作品。是的。
Looks like the works of veterans. Yes.
-都是老兵干的。——正确的。
- All by veterans. - Right.
沃兹的主要慈善事业。
Mr. Voze's primary charity.
他们一直寄来感谢信。
They send them all the time as thanks.
你真是太好了。
That, uh, is very kind.
事实上，我们……呃，退伍军人…莉比，能把药给我吗?
And we, in fact... uh, are veterans... Libby, can I have the remedy, please?
我双手发麻，神经发冷，剧痛。
I've got that numbness in my hands, and the chills in the nerves and shooting pains.
好吗?
Please?
瓦莱丽，请回你的房间或者上楼去。
Valerie, please go into your room or go back upstairs.
你没看见我们有客人吗?
Can't you see we have company present?
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
不。别跟她说话。她身体不舒服。
No. Don't talk to her. She's not well.
瓦莱丽，别跟这些人说话。
Valerie, don't talk to these men.
我不是血友病患者，莉比。我可以和人们交谈。
I'm not a hemophiliac, Libby. I can talk to people.
是的，你不是血友病患者，但你有癫痫，你有神经紊乱。不!
Yes, you're not a hemophiliac, but you are epileptic, and you have a nervous disorder. No!
-我们谈了娃娃的事。-我要咬掉你的耳朵。
- We talked about the doll. - I'll bite your ears off.
不!我告诉过你别对娃娃这么做。
No! I told you not to do that with the doll.
-莫兰太太!卡尔顿……-卡尔顿!
- Mrs. Moran! Carlton... - Carlton!
你知道这让我很不安，瓦莱丽。
You know that disturbs me, Valerie.
你好大的胆子!卡尔顿!
How dare you! Carlton!
卡尔顿。
Carlton.
瓦莱丽,诚实。
Valerie, honestly.
我们说过要把我和她单独留在一起。
We spoke about leaving me alone with her.
进来吧。我们可以在这里谈。
Come in here. We can talk in here.
这种巧合怎么可能?
How is this coincidence even possible?
因为这不是巧合。
Because it's not a coincidence.
是我让莉斯·米金斯雇你们俩的。
I told Liz Meekins to hire you two.
你叫莉斯·米金斯雇我们是什么意思?
What do you mean, you told Liz Meekins to hire us?
她是我的朋友。
She's a friend of mine.
她需要一个她可以信任的人。
She needed someone she could trust.
我们社交圈之外的人。
Someone outside our social circle.
这太奇怪了。
This is so strange.
我从没告诉过你我的真名。
I never really told you my real last name.
班登堡是个流动的名字。
Bandenberg was a traveling name.
但这是我们在阿姆斯特丹的协议。
But that was our deal in Amsterdam.
没有关于过去的事。
Nothing about the past.
对吧?
Right?
你住在新泽西?一直以来?
You live in New Jersey? This whole time?
-是的。-这房子真大。
- Yeah. - This is a big house.
-这就是你的生活方式?-是的。
- This is how you live? - Yeah.
不信。
No letter.
-不是打电话。-我很尴尬。
- Not a phone call. - I was embarrassed.
这不是我曾经的样子。
This is not who I once was.
不是你在阿姆斯特丹遇到的人。
It's not who you met in Amsterdam.
你的平衡有什么问题吗?
What's wrong with your balance?
我有神经障碍。
I have a nerve disorder.
你以前从来没有过。
You never had that before.
不，她以前从来没有过。
No, she never had that before.
我们在这里是有原因的。
We are here for a reason.
哈罗德，别忘了，这事很紧急。
Harold, let's not forget, it's pretty urgent.
瓦莱丽，你认识汤姆·沃兹吗?
Valerie, do you know Tom Voze?
我当然认识汤姆。
Of course I know Tom.
我们有大麻烦了，瓦莱丽。
We're in a lot of trouble, Valerie.
我们需要他为我们担保。
We need him to vouch for us.
他是个好人，但我不知道他会不会为你担保。
He's a good guy, but I don't know if he's gonna vouch for you.
他避免引起争议。他不喜欢那样。
He avoids controversy. He doesn't like that.
他很容易被吓倒。
He's easily intimidated.
-他是你丈夫吗?-卡尔顿在路上了!
- Is he your husband? - Carlton's on his way!
不，他不是我丈夫。
No, he's not my husband.
他娶了一个在外面大喊着要把你赶出去的女人。
He's married to the woman out there screaming to have you kicked out right now.
他是我哥哥。
He's my brother.
我们在阿姆斯特丹经历了那么多，结果伯特和我根本不知道你是谁。
After everything we had in Amsterdam, turns out Burt and I have no idea who you are.
你很清楚我是谁。我很清楚你是谁。
You know exactly who I am. I know exactly who you are.
我们三个。伯特。
All three of us. Burt too.
我们都很了解对方。
We know each other the way it counts.
如果你们俩还有协议，那我也是其中一员。
And if you two still have an arrangement, then I'm still part of it.
也许12年后就不会了。
Maybe not after 12 years.
是的，12年后。是的。
Yes, after 12 years. Yes.
因为我最终来到了这里。
Because I ended up here.
我回来是因为你和你。
And I came back because of you and you.
这是真的。
That's true.
我说过你离开阿姆斯特丹后，会有坏事发生。
I told you when you left Amsterdam, something bad would happen.
我说过这是梦中最糟糕的部分。
I said it would be the bad part of the dream.
我没说过吗?
Did I not say that?
这是真的。
It's true.
现在我们到了。
And here we are.
瓦莱丽，卡尔顿在路上了。
Valerie, Carlton's on his way.
打开门。
Open the door.
我们可以摆脱它。
We can get out of it.
这里不一样，所以我不知道。
Well, it's different here, so I don't know about that.
卡尔顿来了，瓦莱丽。
Carlton is coming, Valerie.
我感觉这是卡尔顿。
I have a feeling this is Carlton.
哦,不。
Oh, no.
不。哦，不，不，不。
No. Oh, no, no, no.
啊…-卡尔顿。卡尔顿。请。——等待。等待……哦!
Ah... - Carlton. Carlton. Please. - Wait. Wait... Oh!
瓦莱丽，你看到发生了什么吗?
Valerie, do you see what happens?
你怎么可能认识这些人?
How do you possibly know any of these men?
他在那儿。白兰地，莫兰太太。
There he is. The brandy, Mrs. Moran.
不用了，谢谢。我不喝酒。
No, thank you. I don't drink.
我觉得我不会相信一个不爱喝酒的人，尤其是在这种时候。
Well, I don't think I trust a man who doesn't like a drink, especially at a time like this.
我的眼睛在哪里，哈罗德?
Where is my eye, Harold?
-就在这里。——谢谢。
- Right here. - Thanks.
我从没想过两个功勋军人会在我家里被打晕。
I never expected two decorated soldiers to get knocked out in my own home.
不，只有一个，先生。
No, just one, sir.
哦，对了，伍德曼先生。你对卡尔顿来说太快了。
Oh, that's right, Mr. Woodman. You were too fast for Carlton.
我是。
I was.
他们和瓦莱丽谈过了，她身体不太好。
They started talking to Valerie, and she's not well.
求你了，亲爱的女孩，别哭了。
And please, darling girl, stop crying.
她哭是很自然的事，莉比。
It's only natural for her to cry, Libby.
她刚发现她的朋友死了。
She just found out her friend is dead.
我们不能永远瞒着她。
We couldn't keep it from her for forever.
我还没病到不能和人说话的地步。
I'm not so ill that I can't talk to people.
你明明知道我认为她应该住院，却把我留在这里和这个病人在一起。-利比。
You leave me here with this invalid when you know very well that I think - she should be hospitalized. - Libby.
-这是为她好-如果你再对我说这种话…-我处理不了…对你来说，那里会更好。
- It's for her own good. - If you ever say that - to me again... - I can't handle... It will be a better place for you.
我就送你去医院
I'll put you in a hospital.
我会送你去女巫审判。
I'll send you to a witch trial.
女士们,请。女士们。停止。
Ladies, please. Ladies. Stop.
我很抱歉。很抱歉我提高了嗓门。
I'm sorry. I'm sorry I had to raise my voice.
她跟这些人说话，好像她认识他们一样。
She was talking to these men like she knows them.
这把我吓坏了。
That terrified me.
你们认识吗?
Do you know one another?
——是的。——没有。
- Yes. - No.
——是的。-确实是这样。
- Yes. - We do, indeed.
欧洲。
Europe.
-阿姆斯特丹来的。-医院
- From Amsterdam. - The hospital.
他们说是圣公会慈善机构的。
They said they were from the Episcopal charities.
这有什么道理吗?
Is there any truth to that at all?
-当然。-部分如此。
- Uh, absolutely. - In part.
部分?
In part?
嘿，晚会马上就要到了。
Hey, the gala is coming up.
这基本上是一个老手的活动。
Mostly a veteran event.
但那里可能有圣公会教徒。
But there might be Episcopalians there.
比尔·米金斯是我们的特邀演讲者。
And Bill Meekins was our featured speaker.
但我们却陷入了这样一个可怕的境地我们被指控杀害了莉兹·米金斯，无论如何这都不是事实。
But we find ourselves in this terrible situation where we're accused of killing Liz Meekins, which is not true in any way.
莉兹提到了"沃兹"这个名字
Liz mentioned the name "Voze,"
所以我们觉得你可能知道是谁在跟踪她能帮我们洗清罪名。
and so we thought you might know who was after her and can help clear our names.
我们的退伍军人。我们尊敬的。
We're veterans. We're respectable.
我们不会掺和进来的，除非帮忙。
We wouldn't be involved in any of this, except to help.
比尔·米金斯是一个爱吃全麦饼干的人。
Bill Meekins was a graham cracker of a man.
他的骨子里一点也不吝啬。
Not a mean bone in his body.
那么为什么……我为什么要帮她?
Then why... Why did I have to help her?
为什么我要鼓励她去找我们认识的所有人，然后雇佣这两个人?
Why did I have to encourage her to go around everyone we know and hire these two?
我确实帮了她，亲爱的。
I did help her, darling.
我让她在事情变糟之前来找我。
I told her to come to me before it got bad.
现在看看发生了什么。
Now look what happened.
是的。看看你做了什么，瓦莱丽。
Yes. Look what you did, Valerie.
我很抱歉，很不幸，但你不应该卷进来。
I'm sorry, it's unfortunate, but you shouldn't have gotten involved.
这不是她的错。
It's not her fault.
-这不是她的错。——汤姆。
- It's not her fault. - Tom.
-这怎么不是她的错?-这不是…-有些事是她的错。——汤姆。汤姆。
- How is this not her fault? - It's not... - Some things are her fault. - Tom. Tom.
哦,汤姆。
Oh, Tom.
她生病了。
She's sick.
我们能找到杀害比尔·米金斯的凶手。
We can find who killed Bill Meekins.
很可能就是杀了他女儿的人。
It's probably the same people who killed his daughter.
我们正在调查。
We're looking into it.
这个信息就能洗清我们的罪名。
And, uh, that information will clear our names.
验尸报告显示他可能是在欧洲时服用过量药物中毒。
Now, the autopsy indicated that he was possibly poisoned by too many medicines while he was in Europe.
你知道他和谁一起来的吗，谁派他来的?
Do you know who he was traveling with, who sent him?
我可以帮你查清楚，但我不能亲自插手。
I can help you find out, but I can't get personally involved.
你是个胆小鬼，汤姆。
You're a coward, Tom.
你竟敢叫他胆小鬼。
Don't you dare call him a coward.
你知道预科学校的孩子们是这么叫他的。
You know that's what he was called by those prep-school kids.
太残忍了，瓦莱丽，你知道的。
It's cruel, Valerie, and you know that.
他们想让我参与所有的委员会，俱乐部。
They want me to get involved in all these committees, clubs.
你知道我是怎么做的吗?
Do you know what I do instead?
我是一个鸟类观察者。
I'm a bird watcher.
这就是我的工作。
That's what I do.
一定很好吧，带你出去。
Mm, it must be good, get you outside.
你是一个观鸟者。他是荒谬的。
You're a bird watcher. He's ridiculous.
他并不比你和你的电影，刀片，茶杯，你做的那些可怕的东西更可笑。
He's no more ridiculous than you are with your movies, razor blades, teacups, the horrid things you make.
说真的，瓦莱丽，他们疯了。
Honestly, Valerie, they're demented.
原谅我。
Excuse me.
你说过你能帮我们找到和他一起去欧洲的人。谁会知道呢?
You said that you could help us find who traveled with him to Europe. Who would know?
吉尔·迪伦贝克会知道的。你认识他吗?
Gil Dillenbeck would know. Do you know him?
全国人民都知道他。
The whole country knows him.
他是美国历史上授勋最多的海军陆战队员。
He's the most decorated Marine in US history.
-是的。-是的，他是。
- Yeah. - Yes, he is.
迪伦贝克是米金斯的朋友。
Dillenbeck was friends with Meekins.
他们都是将军。
They were both generals.
我从没参过军。
I never got involved in the military.
我只是经营家族的纺织公司。
I just ran the family's textile company.
迪伦贝克能告诉你谁和米金斯一起去的。
Dillenbeck can tell you who was traveling with Meekins.
我不会相信其他人。
I wouldn't trust anyone else.
而我自己没有接触到这种信息的渠道。
And I don't have access to that kind of information myself.
-好的，好的。我们见过他两次。-是的。
- Okay, okay. We met him twice. - Yeah.
在比利时和他拍过一次照，还有一次…——华盛顿——红利军行军——在32年夏天。——正确的。
Took a picture with him once in Belgium and another... - D.C. - at the Bonus Army march - in summer '32. - Right.
我们还留着那些照片，沃兹先生。
We still have those pictures, Mr. Voze.
是的。正确的。
Yeah. Right.
他对和谁说话很讲究。
He's very particular about who he'll speak to.
如果你们见过他，你们是他尊敬的士兵，你们的机会比我大得多。
If you've met him, and you're soldiers he respects, your chances are far better than mine.
是的，他不信任有钱的人。
Yeah, he distrusts people of means.
如果你见到他，请一定告诉我们。
If you meet him, please do let us know.
我很想和他握手。
I would love to shake his hand.
莉比在新闻短片里看到了迪伦贝克，她迷上了他。
Libby saw Dillenbeck in the newsreel, and she has a crush on him.
别傻了，瓦莱丽。
Don't be ridiculous, Valerie.
你已经谈到了那个新闻短片。
You have talked about that newsreel.
他是个令人印象深刻的人。
He's a very impressive man.
是的，他是。
Yes, he is.
我正好喜欢那部新闻片。
And I happen to like that newsreel.
别玩了。别玩了，汤姆。
Don't play it. Don't play it, Tom.
我们应该在他们走之前放一放。
Oh, we should play it before they go.
瓦莱丽，吉尔·迪伦贝克也许是你朋友们摆脱麻烦的唯一希望。
Valerie, Gil Dillenbeck is perhaps the one hope your friends have of getting out of all this trouble.
你想看新闻片吗?
Would you like to see the newsreel?
哦,很好。
Oh, good.
去年夏天为福利而游行的退伍军人仍在吉尔·迪伦贝克将军的领导下。
The veterans who marched last summer for benefits remain under the leadership of General Gil Dillenbeck.
尽管这位勇敢的将军仍然是他们的代言人，但退伍军人的福利仍然没有支付。
The veterans' benefits are still unpaid, though the brave general remains their spokesperson.
听着，听着，这让我很生气。
Look, look, it makes me so damn mad.
很多人都说你们是流浪汉。
A whole lot of people speak of you as tramps.
“流浪汉!你们这些人都是流浪汉。”
"Tramps! You men are tramps."
这些人是谁，竟敢这么叫你?
Who are these people who dare call you that?
你是士兵。
You're soldiers.
你们牺牲了自己的生命和四肢。
You sacrificed your lives, your limbs.
你为你的国家受苦了。
You've suffered that for your country.
政府把他们赶出了首都。
The government burned them out of the nation's capital.
退伍军人从未得到过任何福利。
Veterans never got one benefit.
除了你们这些家伙，还有谁为这个国家，为这部法律，为这部宪法，流血牺牲了?
Who in the hell has done all the bleeding for this country, and for this law, and this Constitution anyhow, but you fellows?
汤姆，它毁了新闻片。
Tom, it ruined the newsreel.
我很抱歉，亲爱的。我会把它换掉。
I'm so sorry, darling. I will replace that.
Libby珍贵的新闻短片。
Libby's precious newsreel.
我们在那里。我们和将军合影留念。
We were there. We took pictures with the general.
这么英俊的男人。真是个强壮的男人。
Such a handsome man. Such a strong man.
这才是一个人真正的品质。
Now that is true character in a man.
汤姆的性格也很好。
Tom is also of excellent character.
是的，比起政治，他更喜欢观鸟。
And, yes, he prefers birding to politics.
但它是有意义的。
But it's meaningful.
你说你会回来的。
You said you'd come back.
为什么?这样你就可以离开我了?
Why? So you could leave me?
我不知道我是不是一场短暂的冒险或者你有没有想过我，瓦莱丽。
I didn't know if I was a fleeting adventure or if you even thought about me at all, Valerie.
我从没想过别人。不是真的。
I never thought of anyone else. Not really.
你呢?
What about you?
不。不是真的。
No. Not really.
真的吗?
Really?
是的。
Yes.
你说"尴尬"是什么意思?
And what did you mean, "embarrassed"?
你这话是什么意思?
What did you mean by that?
这么多年都不好意思联系我?
Embarrassed to contact me all these years?
只是看到我这个样子。我…这不是我在阿姆斯特丹时的样子。
Just seeing me like this. I... It's not who I was in Amsterdam.
为了什么?为了什么?
And for what? For what?
在这个国家我们不能在一起。
We can't be together in this country.
你看到那个花园了吗?
You see that garden?
我每天至少在外面待一个小时。
I spend at least an hour out there every day.
-哦，太好了。毫米。
- Oh, that's great. - Mm.
看到玫瑰胸脯的巨嘴鸟，黑眼睛的junco，让我想起上帝的绿色大地。
See a rose-breasted grosbeak, a dark-eyed junco, reminds me of God's green earth.
嗯。
Hmm.
是啊，我不认识那些鸟。但是…有一个来自英国的人违反了观鸟的所有神圣规则，他进入了一种濒临灭绝的鸟类的24个巢穴，取下了24个鸟蛋。
Yeah, I don't know those birds. But... There's this man from England who has violated every sacred rule of birding by going into 24 nests of a near-extinct species of bird to take 24 eggs.
这一切都是为了一个人的自私荣耀为了让他的名字因为一些毫无意义的发现而出现在鸟类书籍上。
All for one man's selfish glorification to get his name in a bird book for some meaningless discovery.
我认为，这种人，很可能会对比尔·米金斯和他的女儿做出可怕的事。
And that is the type of person, I think, who very likely did something awful to Bill Meekins and his daughter.
我正试着跟你走呢，先生。
I'm trying to follow you here, sir.
你是说那个人，那个鸟，英格兰，那个巢，还有那本书，是他杀了比尔·米金斯?
You're saying that man, the bird thing, England, the nest, and the book, that he killed Bill Meekins?
我只是想说明一点。是吗?
I'm trying to make a point. Yeah?
那种男人。
That type of man.
好的。我还是不确定。你是什么意思?
Okay. I'm still not certain. What do you mean?
伯伦森医生，你的药和老兵让你看起来是个好人。
Dr. Berendsen, you seem like a good person with your medicines and your veterans.
你不应该被阻碍。你应该得到帮助。
You shouldn't be hindered. You should be helped.
-但我只是一个人。-长官，我们什么都没做，我们要让警察知道这一点。
- But I'm only one person. - Sir, we didn't do anything, and we need the police to know that.
也许Dillenbeck。
Maybe Dillenbeck.
明天好吗?
Tomorrow?
你明天能再来吗?房子将是空的。
Can you come back tomorrow? The house will be empty.
他们会去另一个家参加莉比的文化讲座，谢谢。
They'll be at the other house for one of Libby's culture talks, please.
嘘。
Shush.
“嘘”是什么意思?你们在做什么?
What do you mean, "shush"? What are you guys doing?
我一直在讨论英国鸟类协会的罪行。
I've been discussing crimes of the bird society of England.
你哥哥有点古怪。
Your brother's a little kooky.
伯特，我不知道发生了什么，但这绝不是米金斯和他女儿的事。
Burt, I don't know what's happening, but it's far beyond Meekins and his daughter.
我现在也不相信我的药物了。
And I don't trust my medications now either.
我们只要找到迪伦贝克就行了。就是这样。
We just have to get Dillenbeck. That's it.
太好了，带我一起去。
Great, take me with you.
-瓦莱丽。-我可以来。我可以帮忙。
- Valerie. - I can come. I can help.
-她可以。这是真的。——伯特。
- She can. It's true. - Burt.
我们三个，形影不离。
The three of us, we were inseparable.
我们做事，我们做事，最重要的是，我们活着。
We did things, we got things done, and most of all, we lived.
——哈罗德?-我必须离开这里-求你了-她说得对。
- Harold? - I have to get out of here, - please! - She's right.
——伯特。她可以帮助我们。-我可以帮忙。
- Burt. She could help us. - I can help.
瓦莱丽?
Valerie?
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
是时候把你的朋友叫到门口了。
It's time to get your friends to the door.
马林医生要来了。
Dr. Malin's coming.
谢谢你能来。抱歉给您添麻烦了。
Thank you for coming. Sorry for the trouble.
谢谢你！这是非常有用的。
Thank you. This turned out very helpful.
很期待。
Looking forward to this.
请代我向卡尔顿告别。
Please say goodbye to Carlton for me.
谢谢你！回头再聊。
Thank you. Talk to you soon.
瓦莱丽?
Valerie?
玛琳医生会带着你要的药过来，记得吗?
Dr. Malin will be here with the remedies you asked for, remember?
你是马林医生吗?
Are you Dr. Malin?
是的。是的，我是。
Yes. Yes, I am.
哦，我是医生。如果你不介意我问一下，以你的专业意见，她的情况如何?
Oh, I'm a doctor. If you don't mind my asking, in your professional opinion, what is her condition?
遗传性神经紊乱。
Hereditary nervous disorder.
影响她的血压，平衡，神经和动作。
Affects her blood pressure, her balance, her nerves and movement.
不，她以前没得过，医生。
No, she never had that before, Doctor.
它随着年龄的增长而增长。
It advances with age.
-谢谢。-谢谢你，医生。
- Thank you. - Thank you, Doctor.
我的上帝。
My God.
真不敢相信我们见到了瓦莱丽。
I can't believe we saw Valerie.
-明天第一件事…-她看起来很好。
- First thing tomorrow... - She looks great.
第一件事……真倒霉，她得了那种病。
First thing... Such bad luck, she got that ailment.
我们去迪伦贝克，希望能进去。
We go to Dillenbeck's, and we hope we get in.
迪伦贝克说不行，伯特。
Dillenbeck said no, Burt.
Dillenbeck说不?
Dillenbeck said no?
什么叫他拒绝了?你和他谈过了吗?
What do you mean, he said no? Did you talk to him?
我和他妻子谈过了。
I talked to his wife.
她说没有。他们的游客太多了。
She said no. They get too many visitors.
我们……我们必须继续努力。
We... We have to keep trying.
你有没有把……我们见面时的照片?
Uh, did you send, uh, the... the... the photographs of when we met him?
不行，因为你得自己带照片来。
No, because you have to bring the pictures yourself.
好吧，哈罗德在哪儿?
All right, where is Harold?
他本该带我去迪伦贝克家的。
He was supposed to take me to Dillenbeck's.
他几小时前就该来了。
He was meant to be here hours ago.
我不知道。
I don't know.
但警察来了，他们想和你谈谈。
But the police are here, and they wanna talk to you.
好的。好吧，一切都要一起来。
Okay. All right, everything all at once.
厄玛·圣克莱尔也在等着。
Irma St. Clair is waiting, also.
哦,上帝!好吧。
Oh, God! All right.
嗯…现在不行。不是现在。
Uh... Peanuts Not now. Not now.
-哦，得了吧。-你确定这里安全吗，瓦莱丽?-是的，很安全。它很好。
- Oh, come on. - Are you sure - this is safe, Valerie? - Yes, it's safe. It's fine.
他们在另一栋房子里。他们会在那里呆一整天。
They're at the other house. They'll be there all day.
还记得这个吗?
Remember this?
你看起来很完美。
You look perfect.
这是你的。
That's you.
为什么?
Pourquoi?
——阿姆斯特丹。-说“阿姆斯特丹”。
- Amsterdam. - Say, "Amsterdam."
阿姆斯特丹。
Amsterdam.
这药肯定更好。
This pill has gotta be better.
当然。
Of course.
莫蒂，这是缓解疼痛和紧张的药。
Morty, it's for the pain and the nerves.
盖特韦勒警探，你想要药。
Detective Getweiler, you want the medicine.
让我来帮你。
Let me do that for ya.
-来吧。-我的屁股疼死了。
- Come on. - This hip is killing me.
不，不，不。来吧。来吧。
No, no, no. Come on. Come on.
把它给我。把它给我。
Give it to me. Give that to me.
我的屁股疼死了。
My hip is killing me.
好了。
There you go.
-太痛苦了。-求你了，求你了。
- So painful. - Please, please, please.
我下次再做吧。朋友是干什么用的?
Let me do that next time. What are friends for?
我想不会再有下次了。
I think there will be no next time.
听我说。
Listen to me.
我们可能要关闭你的办公室了。
We might have to close down your office.
莱姆，把办公室关了?
Lem, close down the office?
是的，关闭你的办公室，是的。
Yeah, close down your office, yeah.
我们需要确凿的证据。
We need hard evidence.
希尔兹警探，你不明白。
Detective Hiltz, look, you don't understand.
我和莱姆，这个和这个。
Me and Lem, this and this.
告诉他，莱姆。
Tell him, Lem.
没错，我们的血液里，大脑里都有金属。想象一下。
Exactly, we got metal in our blood, in our brain. Imagine that.
你的足弓很平。
You have flat arches.
你不能发球。我们理解。
You couldn't serve. We understand.
你们还是我们的头号嫌疑人。
You're still our chief suspects.
为什么?
Why?
为什么?你知道，你知道这不是我们干的。
Why? You know, you know we didn't do this.
不，所有人都说是你干的。
No, everyone says you did it.
每个人都说吗?每一个…有一个人。
Everyone says? Every... There was one man.
-是的。-他做到了。
- Yeah. - He did it.
现在我的队长需要知道你为什么要，秘密地对父亲进行尸检。
Now my captain needs to know why you did that, uh, hush-hush autopsy on the father.
这件事没有什么秘密可言。
There was nothing hush-hush about it.
莉兹·米金斯授权的。完全合法的。
Liz Meekins authorized it. Completely legal.
哈罗德可以证实。
Harold can verify that.
让我们看看尸检结果。
Let's see the autopsy results.
是的，让我把厄玛·圣克莱尔的尸检报告拿过来。
Yes, let me get the autopsy from Irma St. Clair right in here.
对不起，医生。在海外，我知道他们有增强力量的药物。
Excuse me, Doctor. Overseas, I understand that they have medicines for strength.
你这里有什么东西可以增强体力吗?
Do you got anything here for strength?
——什么?——权力?权力。
- What? - Power? Power.
能给我验尸报告吗是的,但是……-来自Irma St. claire…-希尔兹，等等。
Can I get the autopsy report... Yeah, but... - from Irma St. Clair... - Hiltz, wait.
城里最好的验尸护士之一?
One of the best autopsy nurses in the city?
谢谢你！是的，谢谢。
Thank you. Yes, thank you.
乐观。
Optimism.
我知道自从上次见面后我们都过得很不寻常。
I understand we both had a very unusual time since last we saw each other.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
你的外套为什么披在肩上?
Why is your coat over your shoulder?
这就是我想告诉你的。
That's what I wanted to tell you.
我在提交尸检结果的时候，这个满脸通红的人，一脸怒气……-天啊。
I was filing the autopsy results when this red-faced man - with an angry face... - Oh, God.
-还有另一个人…-怎么了?
- And this other man... - What happened?
他们把我推倒，打断了我的手腕，然后拿到了尸检结果。
They threw me down, they broke my wrist, and they took the autopsy results.
他们拿走了一切。
They took everything.
-但那不是…-做得不好。
- But it wasn't... - That's not well done.
-我知道。-那是有角度的。
- I know. - That is angulated.
这需要重新设置，否则情况会非常糟糕。
That needs to be reset, or else that is gonna be very bad.
嗯…-可以吗?——好的。
Uh... - Can I? - Okay.
我来帮你拿外套。-让我坐下。谢谢你！
- Let me take your coat. - Let me sit down. Thank you.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
不，这不是…不是一份好工作。
No, this is not... not a good job.
就是这样。等一等。两个。
That's it. Hold on. Two more.
有一次，你告诉我你是否喜欢西班牙的旋律…——什么?——还是古典音乐?
One time, you were telling me whether you like the Spanish melody... - What? - or was it classical?
经典……就是这样。就是这样。
Classical... That's it. That's it.
全部完成。没关系。
All done. It's okay.
没关系。好了。
It's okay. All right now.
——好吗?——是的。
- Okay? - Yes.
就是这样。我得找个吊绳。
That's it. I gotta get a sling.
-保持支撑。——是的。
- Just keep that supported. - Yes.
我很抱歉把你卷进来了。
I'm so sorry that you got mixed up in all this.
我是验尸护士。
I'm an autopsy nurse.
我卷入了各种各样的事情。
I get mixed up in all sorts of things.
而且，让我离你更近了…
Besides, brought me closer to you and to...
他们在等我们。
They're waiting for us.
让他们等待。
Let them wait.
他为什么在放音乐?
Why is he playing music?
他喜欢音乐。
He likes music.
我不知道他现在为什么要弹。
I don't know why he's playing it now.
你喜欢这种音乐吗?
Do you like this music?
我吗?我不知道。
Me? I don't know.
比阿特丽斯。
Beatrice.
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
这个女人是谁?
Who is this woman?
这是厄玛。我们一起工作。
This is Irma. We work together.
嗯哼。
Mm-hmm.
她是…她是验尸护士。
She's, uh... She's an autopsy nurse.
别跟我胡扯。
Don't give me that.
回家。
Come home.
我会违抗我的家人，这样我们就能在一起了。
I'll defy my family so we can be together.
这是真的吗?
Is this real?
你为什么偏偏现在在这里?
Why are you here now, of all times?
你从没来过这里。
Like, you never come here.
因为雪莉是站在我这边的，她会给我打电话告诉我什么时候该保护我丈夫。
'Cause Shirley's on my side, and she calls me and tells me when to protect my husband.
我父亲控制着你的行医执照
My father controls your medical license.
你知道的。
You know that.
你能让你父母在退伍军人晚会的委员会上签名吗，这样我们就能获得尊重和尊严，你也可以告诉你父母汤姆·沃兹可能会参与进来?
Can you get your parents to put their names on the committee for the gala for the veterans, so we can get respect and dignity, and you can tell your parents that Tom Voze might, uh, get involved?
嗯，是的。
Well, uh, yes.
但你要怎么抓到他?你抓不到他的。
But how will you get him? You won't get him.
我见过他了。
I already met him.
我介绍过你。
I introduced you.
你没介绍我们认识。你跟我们说了他的事，然后我和哈罗德见了他。
Well, you didn't introduce us. You told us about him, and then me and Harold, we met him.
真的很抱歉，伯特。
Really sorry, Burt.
我觉得你应该想想你是谁，你想成为什么。
I think you should think about who you are and what you want to be.
雪莉。不是有益的。
Shirley. Not helpful.
我们需要一个吊绳!
We need a sling!
尸检结果呢?
Where are the autopsy results?
莱姆，她很可能是被推利兹·米金斯的那个人推的。-我拿到弹弓了。
She was rolled, Lem, quite possibly by the same man - who pushed Liz Meekins. - I got the sling.
我可以给你描述一下。他大概……你是说它们被偷了?
I can give you a description. He was about... You mean, they're stolen?
是的，它们被偷了。
Yes, they were stolen.
那么，结果如何呢?
So, what about the results?
我可以告诉你结果。我记得他们。
I can tell you the results. I remember them.
我在他的胃里发现了水银，鲁米诺和安眠药，含量很高。
I found mercury, luminol, and somnifene in his stomach, and they were in high amounts.
我相信是在他生命的最后一周给他的。
I believe they were given to him the last week of his life.
上周，也就是说可能在船上。
Last week, which means probably on the boat.
所以我们没有东西可以给队长，对吧?
So, we don't have anything to give our captain, right?
她刚把证据给你了。
She just gave you the evidence.
我可以给你一份宣誓书。我一直都在做。
I can give you an affidavit. I do them all the time.
我被这座城市束缚住了。
I'm bonded by the city.
怎么样?对吧?
How about that? Right?
-我是说，我们正在做…-还有认证。
- I mean, we are doing... - And certified.
是的。我们在为你做你的工作。
Yes. We're doing your job for you.
那死去的女儿呢?
What about the dead daughter?
把这家伙扔进监狱。
Throw this guy in jail.
让我来处理。
Let me handle this.
——登月舱。登月舱,登月舱。-这是什么…请不要碰那个。
- Lem. Lem, Lem. - What's this... Please do not touch that.
-堕落的茶具?-那是艺术。
- Degenerate tea set? - That is art.
你得把这个处理掉。它是淫秽的。
You gotta get rid of this. It's obscene.
-那是艺术。-不，那不是艺术
- That's art. - No, that's not art.
艺术是美丽的，可爱的，发人深省的。
Art is beautiful, lovely, evokes thoughts.
就是这样。
That's what that is.
-是这样吗?——是的。
- That's what that is? - Yes.
为什么你要拿一套茶具，一个可爱的茶具，把它变成暴力工具?
Why would you take a tea set, a lovely tea set, and turn it into an instrument of violence?
-问得好。-这没道理。
- That's a good question. - It makes no sense.
莱姆，也许是世纪问题。
Perhaps, Lem, the question of the century.
不要想太多。
Don't think about it too much.
——登月舱。——伯特。
- Lem. - Burt.
莱姆，友情在哪里?
Lem, where is the camaraderie?
我们在阿贡河。让我们活下去。
We were in the Argonne. Let's live.
Voulons温文尔雅。
Voulons vivre.
新药丸。记住这一点。
New pill. Remember this.
Souviens-toi。
Souviens-toi.
-你欠我的。——好的。
- You owe me. - Okay.
但你也欠我的。
But you owe me too.
把哈罗德和利兹·米金斯的合同给我。
Get me Harold's contract with Liz Meekins.
我会的。
I will.
真理是可能的。
Truth is possible.
我想，爱，也许，甚至是可能的。
And I think that love, maybe, is even possible.
这个药丸起作用了。
And this pill is working.
真理，爱，还是什么?
Truth, love, what?
哈罗德有辆车。我只有一只眼睛。
Harold has the car. I only got one eye.
-他们不让我开车。-我们会找到他们的
- They don't let me drive. - We'll find them.
没关系。
It's okay.
西班牙夫人，我崇拜你从我第一次见到你的那一晚起我的心就一直渴望着你我还能做什么呢?
Lady of Spain, I adore you Right from the night I first saw you My heart has been yearning for you What else could any heart do?
西班牙夫人，我爱你天哪。
Lady of Spain, I love you Oh, my God.
这听起来很棒。拉里。
This sounds terrific. Larry.
它没有被取消，对吧?
It's not canceled, right?
不是取消了吧?
It's not canceled, is it?
-绝对没有取消。-哦，谢谢。
- Definitely not canceled. - Oh, thank you.
同学聚会太棒了，你要唱歌。
The reunion is a gem, and you're gonna sing.
我们要表演了!
We are going to perform!
你要小心。
You be careful.
弥尔顿!
Milton!
哈罗德几小时前就该来我办公室了。
Harold was supposed to be at my office hours ago.
你没事吧?你看起来不太好。
You okay? You don't look good.
事情变得越来越复杂了，不是吗?
Things have gotten more complicated, haven't they?
你知道吗，我祖父朝一个人的脸开了一枪。
You know, my grandfather shot a guy in the face.
他的脸中枪了。
And he got shot in the face.
不同场合。
Separate occasions.
不同场合。不是同一个人。
Separate occasions. Not the same guy.
一切都解决了。
And it all worked out.
——好。-走吧。
- Good. - Let's go.
Burt博士。伯特。我神经紧绷。
Dr. Burt. Burt. I got a pinched nerve.
不,我……我…我还不知道该怎么办。
No, I'm... I... I don't know what to do with that yet.
我们可以在那里。好的,很好。
We can be right there. Okay, good.
你去哪儿了?我担心死了。
Where have you been? I've been worried sick.
我们开车去兜风，发现了很多东西。
We went on a drive and found out a lot of things.
你本来要去见吉尔·迪伦贝克的，却不能开车出去。
Well, you're not supposed to go for a drive, when you're supposed to meet Gil Dillenbeck.
警察在等你答应他们的文件。
And the police are waiting on papers that you promised them.
有人扇你耳光了吗，伯特?
Did someone slap you, Burt?
因为你脸上有一块红印。
'Cause you have a red mark on your face.
我摔倒了，我被扇了耳光，我…卡尔顿打了我一拳。
I fell, I got slapped, I got... Carlton punched me.
是啊，我当时在场。
Yeah, I was there for that one.
我们也被打了。
We got roughed up too.
我们的处境很尴尬。
We were in quite a situation.
求你了，现在不行。在车里。
Please, not now. In the car.
米尔顿，把这些拿给盖特韦勒警探。好吧?
Milton, get these to Detective Getweiler. All right?
这是莉斯·米金斯的雇佣合同。
This is Liz Meekins's employment contract.
我有说过我预言过一个被关在盒子里的白人会带来极大的麻烦吗?
Did I mention that I predicted extreme trouble from a white man in a box?
然后被一个卡车下的白人女人加了进去。
Then added to by a white woman under a truck.
重点是什么，弥尔顿?
The point, Milton?
你知道吗，我宁愿因为杀了五个白人男人而受审，而不是一个白人女人。
You know, I'd rather be on trial for killin' five white men than one white woman.
因为这会导致一个或多个黑人死在盒子里。
'Cause this can lead to one Black man or more dead in a box.
拜托，我们走吧。
Please, let's get going.
我们几小时前就该去迪伦贝克家了。
We should've left for Dillenbeck's hours ago.
这是我们摆脱警察困境的唯一希望。
That's the only hope that we have to get out of this situation with the police.
我们为什么停在这里?
Why are we stopping here?
这里不是巴克斯县。
This is not Bucks County.
这还没出城呢。
This is not even out of the city.
我们要在华尔道夫酒店稍作停留。
We're making a quick stop at the Waldorf.
迪伦贝克在华尔道夫吗?
Is Dillenbeck at the Waldorf?
我们不是来见迪伦贝克的。
We're not here to see Dillenbeck.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我们在这里做什么?哈罗德,瓦莱丽!
What are we doing here? Harold, Valerie!
难以置信!
Unbelievable!
先生，欢迎光临华尔道夫酒店。
Welcome to the Waldorf Astoria, sir.
还要多久……我们不会住在华尔道夫的。
How long will... We're not staying at the Waldorf.
我们今天只有一件事要做，哈罗德。
We had one thing to do today, Harold.
一件事。试着和吉尔·迪伦贝克谈谈。
One thing. Try to talk to Gil Dillenbeck.
也许还会有个活动…-这就是我的情况…-尊严和…我们今天看到的，伯特。
And maybe have an event with a modicum... - This is my situation... - of dignity and... from my past that we saw today, Burt.
被扭曲的是我内心的平静，伯特。
And it's my peace of mind that's been twisted, Burt.
在我们弄清真相之前，迪伦贝克帮不了我们。
Dillenbeck can't help us until we know what's really going on.
这是怎么回事?
Well, what is going on?
我不知道，但我们会查出来的。
I don't know, but we're gonna find out.
把钥匙给我。
Give me the keys.
-绝对不行。-给我钥匙。
- Absolutely not. - Give me the keys.
你不能开车。你不会开车，你这个独眼疯子。
You're not driving. You can't drive, you one-eyed nut.
哈罗德，这可不明智。
Harold, this is not smart.
至少告诉我这是谁。
At least, just tell me who we're seeing here.
保罗·坎特伯雷。
Paul Canterbury.
保罗·坎特伯雷?
Paul Canterbury?
-是的。是的。-那个玻璃眼的家伙?
- Yeah. Yeah. - The glass-eye guy?
从阿姆斯特丹。恩人吗?
From Amsterdam. The benefactor?
她还在和他们说话，伯特。
She still talks to them, Burt.
-你好，保罗。-瓦莱丽，你好吗?
- Hello, Paul. - Oh, Valerie, how are you?
给你。
There you are.
哈罗德。
Harold.
保罗·坎特伯雷。
Paul Canterbury.
伯伦森，你好吗?
Berendsen, how are you?
给你。深褐色的绿色。
Here you go. Dark hazel green.
——嗯。-一盒六个。
- Eh. - Box of six.
你真是太好了。谢谢你！
Very kind of you. Thank you.
啊!
Ah!
这是喝茶时间。
It's teatime.
只有我喜欢红葡萄酒吗?
Is it just me who fancies claret?
我喜欢一手拿着它，一手拿着茶。
I like to have it going in one hand and tea in the other.
我们现在有点困境，保罗。
We're in a bit of a predicament, Paul.
谢谢你抽出时间来见我们。
Thank you for taking the time to see us.
瓦莱丽，作为绅士，我们愿意做任何必须做的事。
Valerie, we're prepared to do anything we must as gentlemen.
你粗鲁的人!
You bounder!
你作弊!你真让我恶心!
You cheat! You disgust me!
历史会救赎我的。
History will redeem me.
才不会呢。
Like hell it will.
对不起,每一个人。
Sorry, everyone.
没关系。酒水我请。字面上。
It's all right. Drinks on me. Literally.
你好。这边请。
Hello. This way, please.
你记得亨利·诺克罗斯吗?他是那个美国人……他们不需要谈论的联邦雇员，否则我相信他们不会在这里。
You remember Henry Norcross? He's the American... Federal employee they don't need to talk about, or I trust they wouldn't be here.
这一切与英国的“玻璃生意”和华盛顿的融资有什么关系?
What does all of this have to do with a "glass business" in England and, uh, financing in Washington?
它们是重叠的。
Well, they overlap.
有很多事情是重叠的，伯伦森。
Lots of things overlap, Berendsen.
如果你仔细观察，整个世界以最危险的方式重叠在一起。
The whole world overlaps in its most treacherous way if you pay attention.
你们好，伯特，哈罗德，瓦莱丽。
And hello, Burt, Harold, Valerie.
-你好，亨利。-你气色不错，亨利
- Hello, Henry. - You're looking good, Henry.
我也很高兴在我们再次聚集在历史正确的一边时见到你们。嗯?
It's good to see you too as we gather here once more on the right side of history. Huh?
保罗，我知道刚才在茶馆有人把饮料泼到你脸上了。——是的。
Paul, I understand you had a drink thrown in your face - in the tea court just now. - Yes.
只是英格兰的一些旧事，亨利。
Just some old business from England, Henry.
不，不，不。在你脸上喝一杯就是在我脸上喝一杯。
No, no, no. A drink in your face is a drink in my face.
我想听一听。
I'd like to hear about it, please.
然后我们再谈别的事。
Then we'll get on to new business.
他是英国鸟类学会的人。
It was someone from the Ornithological Society of Great Britain.
那些混蛋中的一个，是吧?
Ah, one of those rotten bastards, huh?
是的。
Yeah.
什么?
What?
有人给我讲了一个发生在英国鸟类协会的坏事。
I was told a story about a misdeed in the bird society of England.
我开始怀疑那个故事是不是关于你的。
And I'm starting to wonder if that story is about you.
我们的发现绝非微不足道。
Our discovery was hardly trivial.
是的，我们证明了布谷鸟缺乏建造自己巢穴的能力，礼貌和性格。
Yes, we proved that the cuckoo lacks the capacity, the civility, the character to build its own nest.
哇。
Wow.
这对任何人或任何事来说有什么意义或有趣的呢?
How is that possibly significant or interesting to anybody or anything?
因为这表明杜鹃是一种寄生鸟。
Because it shows that the cuckoo is a parasitic bird.
它欺骗了那些筑巢的好鸟。
It tricks better birds who build nests.
布谷鸟破坏宿主的蛋，然后破坏巢穴本身。
Cuckoo destroys the host's eggs, and then destroys the nest itself.
伯伦森，布谷鸟根本不在乎。好吗?
Berendsen, the cuckoo doesn't give a damn. Okay?
我想说，这是对自然界包括人类在内的寄生破坏行为的深刻阐述。-听着，听着。
I'd say it's a profound statement on the parasitic destructive behavior of nature, - including humans. - Hear, hear.
在我们今天看到的事情之后，这一点尤其正确。
That is especially true after what we saw today.
伯特，这是关于我们遭遇的故事。听好了。
Burt, it's the story about what happened to us. Listen up.
我们一直想告诉你，伯特。
We have been trying to tell you, Burt.
我觉得保罗和亨利也该听听。
And I think Paul and Henry should hear this too.
但我们今天去了一个很奇怪的诊所发现了这个。
But we ended up at a very strange clinic today and we found this.
这些符号到处都是。
Those symbols were everywhere.
你以前见过吗?
Have you seen it before?
五人委员会。
The Committee of the Five.
按照我们的约定，我去见了瓦莱丽，但我们注意到有人在监视我们。
I went to see Valerie as we'd arranged, but then we noticed somebody was watching us.
有人隔着窗帘看着我们。
Someone was watching us through the curtains.
就是他推了莉斯·米金斯。
That's the man who pushed Liz Meekins.
他一定是等得不耐烦了因为他要走了，然后我们决定跟踪他。
And he must've got bored waiting because he started to leave, and then we decided to follow him.
他带我们去了罗克兰县。
And he led us to Rockland County.
去了一栋没有标志的砖房。
To an unmarked brick building.
他们以为我们是做手术的病人。
They assumed that we were patients for a procedure.
消毒。
To be sterilized.
强制绝育诊所。
Ah, a forced sterilization clinic.
然后我看到了那个人。
Then I saw the man.
这个红脸男人。推利兹·米金斯的人。
This red-faced man. The man who pushed Liz Meekins.
他看着我，然后说…这是你结束自卑的时刻。
He looked right at me, and he said... This is your moment to end your inferiority.
你要做这个手术。
You're gonna have that procedure.
不要动!
Don't move!
大便。
Shit.
谁去叫船长!
Somebody call the captain!
-来吧。-阻止那些人!
- Come on. - Stop those people!
——帮助!我们需要帮助!-叫舰长!
- Help! We need help! - Call the captain!
瓦莱丽的枪走火的时候，打中了一块玻璃，我们离开了那里，回城里去了。-天啊。
Well, when Valerie's gun finally went off, it hit a glass, and we got out of there - and headed back to the city. - My God.
我很高兴你没事。
Well, I'm glad you're all right.
但如果你没有拿到红脸杀手的身份证明，那就毫无用处了。
But if you didn't get the red-faced killer's identification, then it's of no help, whatsoever.
你在说什么，伯特?
What are you talking about, Burt?
它与一切都有关系。
It has everything to do with everything.
今天，所发生的一切，不得不……——如何?-从我开始。
Today, that what happened, has to... - How? - It starts with me.
好吧，从我开始。
Well, it starts with me.
我告诉德克萨斯州朗维尤的一些朋友，不要去这个非常恐怖的诊所，就像我们今天看到的那样。
I told some friends in Longview, Texas, not to visit this very horrifying clinic, a lot like the one we saw today.
一群暴徒。一群白人追我。
A mob. A mob of white men chased me.
他们骚扰我。他们想杀我。
They harassed me. They tried to kill me.
他们没有成功。他们非常不成功。
They were unsuccessful. They were very unsuccessful.
我离开了德州朗维尤，再也没回头。
I left Longview, Texas, and I never looked back.
不只是你和德州的事，也不只是今天洛克兰的事。
It's not just about you and Texas, nor today in Rockland.
有一个组织希望在全世界范围内这样做。
There is an organization that wishes to do this all over the world.
这是什么意思?
What does it mean?
这意味着这个国家有一个阴谋集团和德国的另一个阴谋集团有联系他们支持这些诊所，想要统治世界。
It means there's a cabal in this country tied to another in Germany who supports these clinics, who want to rule the world.
统治世界?
Rule the world?
完全正确的。
Exactly correct.
阴谋集团里有谁?
Who's in the cabal?
也许问谁是错误的问题。而是要问为什么。
Maybe who is the wrong question to ask. Instead ask why.
去找迪伦贝克。
Go see Dillenbeck.
问他为什么他的同事米金斯将军被杀了。
Ask him why his fellow, General Meekins, was murdered.
迪伦贝克，他一直在领导这个阴谋集团想弄清楚他们是谁，有什么计划。
Dillenbeck, he's been leading on this cabal to find out who they are, what they plan.
五人委员会。
Committee of the Five.
该组织名为Der Fünf。
The organization named Der Fünf.
五人委员会。
Committee of the Five.
想弄清楚他们是谁。
Trying to figure out who they are.
五人委员会。
Committee of the Five.
-是的。-是的。
- Yeah. - Yeah.
我觉得如果迪伦贝克能在你的同学会上发言就太好了。
I think it would be wonderful if Dillenbeck was the speaker at your reunion.
看来你的活动越来越重要了，伯伦森。
Seems your event's becoming rather important, Berendsen.
如果你能让迪伦贝克开口，也许能吸引到阴谋集团中更有影响力的成员。
If you can get Dillenbeck to speak, perhaps it might attract more influential members of the cabal.
是啊，是街上的杀手还是高层为这一切埋单。
Yeah, the killer from the street or the higher-ups paying for it all.
等等，等等，等等，等等。
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
不。我不希望我们的活动，哈罗德和我的活动，被任何人这样利用。
No. I don't want our event, Harold's and my event, to be used like this by anybody.
使用?不。
Used? No.
就当这是在保护你所爱的人。
Think of it as protecting what you love.
好吗?
Okay?
我们在阿姆斯特丹告诉过你我们会来拜访你，现在我们来了。
We told you in Amsterdam we'd come a-calling, and here we are.
给你。
And here you are.
我们谈完了吗?
Well, we done here?
还是你想多聊聊鸟类?
Or you wanna talk more about birds?
你知道吗，很多人认为这是关于…宁静:与自然的宁静或交流
You know, a lot of people assume that it's about the, uh... the tranquility or the communion with nature.
但我发现观鸟是如此迷人，因为它迫使你决定你在看什么。
But I find bird-watching so fascinating because it forces you to decide what you are looking at.
我在磨练我的鉴别力。
I am honing my art of discernment.
我希望你们相信我，我相信现在是干预的时候了。
And I want you to trust me that I believe now is the time to intervene.
我们请吉尔·迪伦贝克做这次活动的演讲者，他就会像磁铁一样吸引所有的钉子把这个充满背叛的房子推倒在地。
We get Gil Dillenbeck to be the speaker at this event, he will be the magnet that draws all the nails out of the wood and brings this house of treachery down to the ground.
你说呢，伯特?拜托。
So what do you say, Burt? Please.
请你试试，伯特。
Please try, Burt.
我不想说"我早告诉过你"
I don't like to say, "I told you so,"
但这一切比我们所有人想象的都要大得多。
but this is all turning out to be a lot larger than any of us imagined.
是的。
Yeah.
如果晚会是保罗用的…-你没事吧?-你没事吧?
If the gala is used by Paul... - Are you okay? - You good?
嗯哼。好吧。它来了又去。我很好。
Mm-hmm. Fine. It comes and goes. I'm fine.
是吗?
Yeah?
你感觉很好，然后突然眩晕，你感到头晕……它来了又去。
You feel fine, then all of a sudden, vertigo, you get dizzy... It comes and goes.
首先，他们告诉我，我患有癫痫。
First, they told me that I had epilepsy.
我从来没有发作过，但他们说我有癫痫，而且癫痫迟早会发作。
I'd never had a seizure, but they said I had epilepsy, and the seizures would come sooner or later.
但如果我服用药物，这是可以避免的。
But that could be avoided if I took medication.
我就这样做了。
And so I did.
然后我开始出现其他症状，更多的症状，他们说，“这是遗传的。”
And then I started having other symptoms, more symptoms, and they said, "That's hereditary."
“那是你母亲的遗传。”
"That's from your mother's side."
所以他们给了我新的药物，我一直在服用。
So they gave me new medications, and I kept taking that.
现在一年又一年过去了，我几乎不出家门，我感觉自己像个病人，活不下去了，我……我开始怀疑这一切了。
And now years and years have gone by and I'm barely leaving the house, and I feel like I'm a patient, and I can't live, and I... I'm starting to question all of it.
-你没事吧?——嗯。
- You okay? - Mm-hmm.
不，别碰我。别抱着我。
No, don't touch me. Don't hold me.
我很好。我能做到，我只需要…我只是需要在这里休息一下，只是……-天啊。你好吗?——婊子。
I'm fine. I can do this, and I just need... I just need a minute here to rest, just... - Oh, God. You good? - Bitch.
-瓦莱丽。-哦，是的。
- Valerie. - Oh, yes.
我很好。
I'm fine.
看，我在爬楼梯。
Look, I'm doing stairs.
我上楼梯也不会头晕。
I can go up stairs with no vertigo.
没有眩晕。我很好。我能跑。
No vertigo. I'm fine. I can run.
-哦，天哪…瓦莱丽!-瓦莱丽!
- Oh, my... Valerie! - Valerie!
带着那个喝醉的女人走!
Collect that drunk woman and go!
我们认识将军。
We know the general.
-我们有照片。-我没事，该死
- We have pictures. - I'm all right, damn it.
好了，我不要那些照片。
There, I don't want the pictures.
-快走!-我是医生。
- Go, now! - I'm a doctor.
-现在就走。-我是老兵。
- Go now. - And I am a veteran.
-你需要一个医生…-谢谢。
- You're gonna need a doctor... - Thank you.
-等我解决了你。——呼吸。简单呼吸就好。
- When I'm through with you. - Breathe. Just breathe.
快走，不然我就报警了。
Now, go or I'm gonna call the police.
-就几分钟…-不，我来吧。我做的事。
- Just a few minutes... - No, I've got it. I do.
-你丈夫的时间。——没有。
- Of your husband's time. - No.
我一定要战胜这些症状-走了…我并没有因此而沮丧。
I have to fight through these symptoms - at some point. - There goes... I'm not getting depressed about it.
我们洗清罪名的唯一机会。
Our one chance to clear our names.
你得换药，换医生。
You have to change your medicine and your doctor.
狗娘养的。我很好。
Son of a bitch. I was fine.
也许我该走了。
Maybe it's time for me to leave anyway.
离开是什么意思?
What do you mean, leave?
就算我们三个把米金斯解决了，坐牢的还是我。
Well, even if we solve Meekins out of the three of us, I'm the one that's going to jail.
-系统被操纵了。——哈罗德。
- The system's rigged. - Harold.
我从一开始就告诉过你，这份工作不是个好主意。
I told you from the get-go, this job was a bad idea.
弥尔顿告诉过你这份工作不是个好主意…
Milton told you this job was a bad idea...
但她得帮我们找到工作。
but she had to get us hired.
哦,“她”吗?“她得去……”
Oh, "she"? "She had to get..."
"她"还把你从监狱里救了出来，你好像忘了很多。
"She" also got you out of jail, which you seem to forget a lot.
你不能现在就不理我。
You can't turn your backs on me now.
你违反了约定，记得吗?
You broke the pact, remember?
我毁约了?什么时候?
I broke the pact? When?
我们告诉过你别走，伯特。
We told you not to leave, Burt.
至少你找到了爱，即使你得不到。
At least you found love, even if you can't get it.
我从来没那么幸运知道那到底是什么。
I've never been lucky enough to even know what the hell it is.
这种可怕的痛苦我不希望发生在任何人身上。
And that's a terrible affliction I don't wish on anyone.
我真希望我从没找到过它。
I wish I never did find it.
因为太疼了。
Because it hurts too much.
等等!
Wait!
将军想见你。
The general wants to meet you.
别搞砸了。
Don't screw this up.
-振作起来。-来吧!
- Straighten up. - Come on!
扶我走。
Help me walk.
之前的误会我很抱歉。
I'm sorry about the misunderstanding before.
不要紧。不要紧。
Never mind. Never mind.
我们这里有很多不速之客。
We get so many uninvited guests here.
-当然。-我们不想见到的人。
- Of course. - People we don't want to see.
-对不起。-谢谢。
- I'm sorry. - Thank you.
我没醉。
I'm not drunk.
小姐，你怎么了?你还好吗?
Uh, young lady, what is wrong with you? Are you all right?
有点眩晕，还有一些其他的…我现在正在停药。
It's a touch of vertigo and a couple of other... I'm coming off some medication at the moment.
我有过眩晕症，但世界一直在转。
I had vertigo once and the world just keeps moving.
我想请你喝一杯，但我们家没有酒。
I'd offer you a drink, but we don't keep alcohol in the house.
哦，那很好。
Oh, that's fine.
你可以把你的帽子和外套放在那边。
You can put your hat and coats over there.
你往这边走。
You're going up this way.
我们要赶在另一个客人前面吗?
Are we jumping ahead of another visitor?
马奎尔先生每个月都来讨论一些我丈夫永远得不到明确答复的问题。
Oh, Mr. Maguire comes every month to discuss something my husband can never get a clear answer about.
对吧，马奎尔先生?
Right, Mr. Maguire?
啊。
Ah.
我知道什么?
What do I know?
我只是想做鱼汤因为将军曾经在法国做过。
I'm just trying to make bouillabaisse because the general had it once in France.
将军?你的客人来了。
General? Your visitors are here.
你管你丈夫叫“将军”?
You call your husband "General"?
只在工作日。
Only on the weekdays.
你周末叫他什么?
What do you call him on weekends?
这是一个非常私人的问题。
That's a very personal question.
没人教过你礼貌吗?
Were you taught no manners?
别怪我害我们被赶出来了。
Don't blame me for getting us kicked out.
-我没有别的意思。-你紧张吗?
- I didn't mean anything by it. - Are you nervous?
她有一半时间都在开大家的玩笑。
She's pulling everybody's leg half the time.
这就是我爱她的原因。
That's why I love her.
太荣幸了，先生。
What an honor, sir.
是照片让你改变主意不想见我们了吗?
Um, was it the pictures that made you change your mind about seeing us?
我怎么知道照片里的人真的是你?
How can I know this is you, really, in the picture?
是的，先生。
Uh, yes, sir.
好吧，我是医生。
So, well, I'm the doctor.
她是护士。他是律师。
She's the nurse. He's the attorney.
我们都是在比利时认识的，如果你还记得的话，那是我们第一次见面的地方。
We all met in Belgium, which, if you recall, is where we met for the first time.
还有去年夏天在华盛顿举行的B.E.F.三月。
As well as Washington, last summer, at the B.E.F. March.
我告诉你一件我记得很清楚的事。
I'll tell you one thing that I can remember quite clearly.
你做了一件…我相信你唱了一首歌。
You did something that... You sang a song, I believe.
哪一个哪一个，先生?
Which... Which one, sir?
好吧，这是要你记住的。
Well, that's for you to remember.
我见了成千上万的人。你才见过我两次。
I met thousands of people. You just met me twice.
所以，你应该记住这首歌。
So, you should remember the song.
我想让你现在唱，然后我就知道是你了。
I'd like you to sing it now, then I'll know it's you.
唱首歌。
Sing a song.
你曾见过梦吗-梦游?——走?
Did you ever see a dream - Dream walking? - Walking?
嗯，我做了是的…你曾听过一个梦吗?说话吗?
Well, I did Yes... Did you ever hear a dream... Talking?
看到……正确的。
See... Right.
然后我做了哦，不，不。这是……不是这样的。
Then I did Oh, no, no. That's... That's not it.
嗯…是用法语写的吗?
Um... Was it in French?
我一听到就知道了。
I'll know it when I hear it.
是的。就是这样。
Yes. That was it.
这是正确的。
That's right.
我们瞎编的。
We made it up.
这是说不通的。
Well, it's not supposed to make sense.
这只是一首毫无意义的歌。
It's just a nonsense song.
但它让我们感觉很好。
But it makes us feel good.
-你是医生吗?-是的，先生。
- And you're the doctor? - That's right, sir.
你在一天内疏散了四千人。
And you evacuated 4,000 men in one day.
你很有名。
You're very famous.
不同的医生。
Different doctor.
那是旧金山来的社交男。
That's the social guy from San Francisco.
我的人生故事。
Story of my life.
不是你?
Not you?
伯特和我在一天内疏散了几千人，长官。
Burt and I did evacuate a couple of thousand men in one day, though, sir.
还有你，先生，你用刀捅了30个德国人，他们叫你黑死病?
And you, sir, you stabbed 30 Germans with your knife, and they called you "Black Death"?
不，先生，那是黑死病亨利·约翰逊。
No, sir, that was Black Death Henry Johnson.
但在他们给我这个之前，我确实得到了12个。——哦。
But I did get 12 of 'em - before they gave me this. - Oh.
我还救了很多人的命。
I also saved a lot of lives.
-真的吗?-是的。
- You did? - Yeah.
那是件值得骄傲的事。
Well, that's something to be proud of.
他们让你穿那些法国制服真是可耻。
It's shameful they made you wear those French uniforms.
你应该穿你自己国家的制服。
You should wear your own country's uniform.
从你嘴里传到上帝的耳朵里，先生，谢谢你。
From your mouth to God's ears, sir. Thank you.
那么，将军?
So, uh, General?
比尔Meekins。
Bill Meekins.
比尔·米金斯是我的朋友，他和他女儿的遭遇真是个悲剧。
Well, Bill Meekins was a friend of mine, and it's a tragedy what happened to him and his daughter.
没人关心这事真是太丢脸了。
And it's a disgrace that no one cares.
-哦，我们在乎。——事实上。
- Oh, we care. - Indeed.
其实是已故的伊丽莎白·米金斯雇的我们。
The late Elizabeth Meekins hired us, actually.
她雇了你?为什么?
She hired you? Why?
她不相信她父亲是自然死亡。
She didn't believe that her father died of natural causes.
在从欧洲回来的路上。
On his way back from Europe.
我最后一次和我朋友通话时，他从罗马给我打电话。
The last time I spoke to my friend, he called me from Rome.
从酒店打电话给我。
Called me from the hotel.
告诉我他看到了什么可怕的东西。
Told me of something monstrous that he had seen.
使他大为不安。
Disturbed him greatly.
这就是比尔被杀的原因。
That was why Bill was killed.
你进来的时候看到楼下那个人了吗?
You see the man downstairs when you came in?
每隔几周，他就会来…-你看到一个包了吗?——嗯。
Every couple of weeks, he comes and he brings... - Did you see a bag? - Mm-hmm.
他给了我一袋钱。
A bag of money he offers to me.
钱干什么?
Money for what?
发表演讲
To give a speech.
他不肯告诉我谁在背后支持他。我问他。
He won't tell me who's behind him. I ask him.
然后问:“这是谁送的?”
And say, "Who's this from?"
但他没有给我答案。
And he doesn't give me an answer.
他们付钱让你做他们的喉舌。
They're paying you to be their mouthpiece.
没错，完全正确。
That's right, exactly.
他们知道老兵们也会跟随。
And they know the veterans will follow.
五人委员会。
The Committee of the Five.
有人在试图做一些黑暗而奸诈的事。
Well, somebody is trying to do something dark and treacherous.
到这里来。
Come here.
问他愿不愿意在晚会上讲话。
Ask him if he'll speak at the gala.
进一步推进。就像亨利说的。
Push it further. Like Henry said.
先生，如果这些人要见你…——嗯。
Sir, um, if these guys - are meeting you... - Hmm.
如果你想找出幕后黑手是谁，为什么不更进一步把他们带到我们的重聚晚会上呢?
And you wanna find out who's behind it all, why not go further and lead them to our reunion gala event?
他们可能会以某种方式表现出来。
They might show themselves in some fashion.
马奎尔，你能告诉我，你为什么每个月都来?
Maguire, can you tell me, why do you come every month?
将军，我不能在别人面前说这件事。
Well, General, I can't speak about it in front of other people.
为什么不呢?我是说，你说没什么好隐瞒的。
Well, why not? I mean, you say there's nothing to hide.
这是为了一个好的事业。
And it's in the name of a good cause.
是的，先生，但不是每个人都明白。
Well, yes, sir. But not everyone understands it.
我不明白的是你代表的是谁。
What I don't understand is who or what you represent.
你能告诉我吗?
Can you tell me?
我无权透露我代表谁，先生。
Well, I'm not at liberty to say who I represent, sir.
但他们都是非常重要的人，他们有一个非常重要的组织会让一切变得更好。
Uh, but they are very important people, and they have a very important organization that's gonna change everything for the better.
正如我告诉过你的，先生，我们的目的是在经济危机时期正确地领导这个国家。
The purpose, as I've told you, sir, is to lead this nation properly in this time of economic crisis.
白宫里有个瘸子。
There's a cripple in the White House.
罗斯福是软弱的。我们希望你代表退伍军人和新领导层发言。
Roosevelt is weak. We'd like you to speak on behalf of the veterans and new leadership.
这就是选举的意义，马奎尔。
Well, that's what elections are for, Maguire.
你不相信宪法吗?
Don't you believe in the Constitution?
当然，但我们认为现在迫切需要采取行动。
Of course, but we feel that action is urgently needed now.
从一个退休将军那里得到的吗?
From a retired general before the election?
你想让我当独裁者吗?
Do you want me to be a dictator?
这是你的大赞助商想要的吗?
Is that what your big sponsors want?
呃,…一个独裁者?
Uh, a... A dictator?
不，没必要这么说。
No, it doesn't have to be said like that.
总理?这样会更好吗?
Okay, chancellor? Does that make it better?
这仍然违反宪法。
It still violates the Constitution.
他们在德国和意大利的老兵身上做了这个实验。
They did this with veterans in Germany and Italy.
很成功。
Very successful.
先生，五人委员会捐了一万八千人。
18,000, sir, from the Committee of the Five.
健全美元委员会。
Uh, Committee for a Sound Dollar.
-从谁那里?-五人委员会?
- From who? - Committee of the Five?
健全美元委员会。
Committee for a Sound Dollar.
国家需要你们的领导。
The nation needs your leadership.
你明白我在说什么吗，先生?
Do you see where I'm going, sir?
马奎尔先生，我改变主意了。
Mr. Maguire, I've changed my mind.
我决定由我来演讲。
I've decided I will do the speech.
这非常令人兴奋。
This is very exciting.
我来选活动。我和比尔·米金斯从他创建的军团中认识的老兵们交谈是最舒服的。我会在他们的聚会上讲话。
I'll choose the event. I'm most comfortable speaking with the veterans Bill Meekins knew from the regiment he created. I'll speak at their reunion.
当然，但是……因为我想见见把钱放进包里的人。
Of course, but... Because I want to see the men who put the money in that bag.
我想看着他们的眼睛，和他们握手。
And I wanna look them in the eye, and I wanna shake their hand.
鉴于我们现在是合作伙伴了，我可以保证你会见到健康美元委员会的各位先生。
Given that we're partners now, I can guarantee that you will meet the distinguished gentlemen on the Committee for a Sound Dollar.
他们会亲自去见你，不过我们可能需要在一个私人房间。
They will be there to meet you personally, although we might need to be in a private room.
——好的。-谢谢。
- Okay. - Thank you.
这太棒了。这是演讲。
This is wonderful. This is the speech.
马奎尔先生，拿着那个包。
Mr. Maguire, take that bag.
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
所以你还是不肯告诉我他们是谁。
So, you still won't tell me who they are.
这是真的吗?
Is that true?
在活动上，先生。
At the event, sir.
谁给我更多的钱，告诉我该说什么……而我在演讲中没有说的话很可能害死了比尔·米金斯和他的女儿。
Whoever offers me more money and tells me what to say... and what not to say in my speech very likely killed Bill Meekins and his daughter.
他是这一切的幕后黑手。
And is behind all this.
就这样，两名士兵和一名护士发现我们和伟大的，光荣的迪伦贝克将军结成了联盟。
And so, two soldiers and a nurse found ourselves in league with the great honorable, decorated General Dillenbeck.
将军，你真该和汤姆·沃兹谈谈，瓦莱丽的哥哥。
General, you should really speak to Tom Voze, Valerie's brother.
请到7号生产室。
Production Room 7, please.
7号生产室，需要机械师。
Production Room 7, mechanic needed.
从没见过。
Never saw that.
也许是……也许是现代艺术。
Maybe it's... Maybe it's modern art.
我真想过去看看。
Kinda wanna go over there and take a look at it.
我想在阿姆斯特丹再试一次。
I would like to try again in Amsterdam.
你会吗?
You would?
是的。
Yes.
好吧，希望一切顺利。
Well, let's hope this goes well.
Voze先生。
Mr. Voze.
——伯特。我可以叫你汤姆吗?
- Burt. - May I call you Tom?
-当然。-沃兹夫人。
- Of course. - Mrs. Voze.
让我给你介绍迪伦贝克将军。
Let me introduce you to General Dillenbeck.
将军。
General.
迪伦贝克将军，很高兴见到你。
General Dillenbeck, it is such a pleasure to meet you.
我认为你是一个有荣誉和力量的人，而且是一个……这样一个……真的很有尊严，很美好，我真的相信你说的一切。
I think you are a man of such honor and strength, and such a... Such a... Truly just so dignified and wonderful, and I truly believe everything that you say.
嗯…利比。
Uh... Libby.
这样一个……哦,苏……这样一个……str……强……她太兴奋了。
Such a... Uh, su... Such a... str... strong... She's so excited.
非常激动。不当的兴奋。
Very excited. Inappropriately excited.
你曾在电台做过现场直播吗?
Have you ever broadcast live on the radio?
联欢晚会吗?不,从来没有。
The gala? No, never.
你能想象吗?
Well, can you imagine?
想想你在密歇根的切博伊根或伊利诺伊州的卡本代尔的老朋友们，坐在家里，听着收音机，听着你的歌，伯特。
Think of your veteran friends in Cheboygan, Michigan, or Carbondale, Illinois, sitting at home, listening to the radio, hearing your songs, Burt.
——哇。-还有你的演讲，将军。
- Wow. - And your speech, General.
马奎尔给我的演讲?
The speech Maguire gave me?
不。不不不不不。你的演讲。
No. No, no, no, no, no. Your speech.
你要做的演讲。
The speech you want to give.
我…我不知道马奎尔是谁。
I... I don't know who Maguire is.
但我要你说出真心话为比尔·米金斯辩护。
But I want you to speak from your heart to vindicate Bill Meekins.
还有那些被遗弃的无声老兵。
And all those voiceless veterans who've been abandoned.
是的。
Yes.
你带路。那些烂苹果，不管他们对比尔·米金斯做了什么，都会暴露的。
You lead the way. And the rotten apples, whatever they did to Bill Meekins, will reveal themselves.
我要按我的方式演讲。我想说出真相。
I'll give the speech my way. I wanna tell the truth.
诀窍是让五人委员会和马奎尔认为……
The trick was to let the Committee of Five and Maguire think...
将军将为白宫的新领导层发表演讲。
the general would give their speech for new leadership in the White House.
立即。没有选举。
Immediately. No election.
骗老兵支持它。
Conning the veterans into supporting it.
而汤姆，如承诺的那样，帮我们摆脱了警察的圈套，让我们非常惊讶的是，警察现在和我们在一起，共同计划阻止这一切。
And Tom, as promised, had gotten us off the hook with the police who now, to our great surprise, were together with us, united in this plan to stop it.
我们都支持将军。
And we all supported the general.
他在用自己做诱饵。
He was using himself as bait.
晚上好，美国。
Good evening, America.
我是威尔金·哈茨代尔在一年一度的退伍军人重聚晚会上为您直播。
This is Wilkin Hartsdale broadcasting to you live from the annual Veterans Reunion Gala.
保罗,亨利。
Paul, Henry.
他是来找你的。他有问题。
He's here for you. He has questions.
坎特伯雷诺。
Norcross, Canterbury.
我从没见过，乔治·华盛顿这么大的照片。
I've never seen, uh, such a big picture of George Washington.
让我问一个非常简单的问题。
Let me ask a very simple question.
你们到底站在哪一边?
Whose side are you guys on?
我们当然是站在你这边的。
We're on your side, of course.
同一个上帝，不同的教会。
Same God, different church.
同样的女士，不同的衣服。我们是一条船上的。
Same lady, different dress. We're on the exact same side.
帮我个忙。
Do me a favor.
仔细给我解释一下，因为我要做的事可能会赔上我的命。
Explain this to me very carefully 'cause I'm about to do something that could cost me my life.
这一切的诀窍在于，要等到最后一秒尽可能多地揭露我们所能捕捉到的犯罪行为。
The trick with all this is, is to wait till the absolute very last second to expose as much of the criminality as we are able to capture.
-我的钱?-不，先生，-绝不以你为代价-不，上帝。不，不，先生。
- At my expense? - No, sir, - never at your expense. - No, God. No, no, sir.
-不先生-绝不以你为代价-求你了-今晚在这里有很多我在乎的人。
- No, sir. - Never at your expense, - please. - There's a lot of people I care about here tonight.
相信我们的洞察力，将军。
Trust our powers of discernment, General.
是的，布谷鸟在巢里，布谷鸟就要被困住了。
Yes, the cuckoo is in the nest, and the cuckoo is about to be trapped.
杜鹃?
Cuckoo?
请让我们开晚会吧。
And please, let us have our gala.
让我们庆祝我们的生活。
Let us celebrate our lives.
抓住那个杀了米金斯的混蛋还有那些想劫持政府的混蛋。
Get the son of a bitch who killed Meekins and those bastards who wanna hijack our government.
是吗?
Yes?
我希望这个狗娘养的能成功。
I hope this son-of-a-bitch thing works.
-不然我们就完蛋了——嗯。
- Or else we're fucked. - Hmm.
欢迎来到第369、42和33届纽约团的第14届年度晚会。
Welcome to the 14th annual gala for the 369th, 42nd, and the 33rd New York regiments.
今晚的娱乐节目继续由Berendsen医生主持花生——这看起来很有前景。-很有希望，亨利。
This evening's entertainment continues with Dr. Berendsen, the medical officer... Peanuts - This looks promising. - Very promising, Henry.
花生如果你没有香蕉，别蓝了装在小包里的花生在叫你不要浪费它们不会肚子疼你醒来的时候会尝尝花生我是说，他很好。
Peanuts If you haven't got bananas, don't be blue Peanuts in a little bag are calling you Don't waste them No tummy ache You'll taste them When you awake Peanuts I mean, he is good.
-他有点瘪了。-那你去吧。
- He's a little bit flat. - Well, you do it.
花生
Peanuts
是的,好极了!
Yeah, bravo!
谢谢你们，韦恩·卡托斯基和维克多·巴恩斯!
Thank you, Wayne Katowski and Victor Barnes!
我的天啊!
Oh, my God!
是的,伯特!哇!
Yes, Burt! Whoo!
是的。这是盖特韦勒警探。
Yeah. So, there's Detective Getweiler.
是的。
Yeah.
哈罗德。迪伦贝克就在那里。
Harold. And Dillenbeck's right there.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
Berendsen博士说他相信——音乐是药物……——托尼!
Dr. Berendsen says he believes - music is medicine... - Tony!
为每一个受伤的老兵。
For each and every one of these wounded veterans.
——弗雷德!拉里!——哇!
- Fred! Larry! - Wow!
-你叫什么名字?-阿尔弗雷德，长官。
- What's your name? - Alfred, sir.
是范登休维尔夫妇吗?
Is that the Vandenheuvels?
等一下，音乐将继续。
In just a moment, music will continue.
是的。
Yes.
那是范登休维尔医生和他的妻子，那是比阿特丽斯。
That's Dr. Vandenheuvel and his wife, and that's Beatrice over there too.
稍后的节目中……——哦!
Coming up later - on in the program... - Oh!
我们为你感到骄傲。
We're very proud of you.
哇!这是多么不同的一天啊。
Wow! What a difference a day makes.
我要把剃须用具拿回去吗?
Should I move my shaving kit back in?
-希伯来人的幽默感。——父亲。
- That Hebrew sense of humor. - Father.
我觉得是时候让医学委员会重新评估你的情况了，孩子。
I think it's time that the medical board reassessed your situation, son.
我能做到。我很乐意。
I can make that happen. I'd be happy to.
哇。
Whoa.
你听到了吗?
Did you hear that?
这是一个完美的夜晚!
It's a perfect evening!
这终于发生了。
This is happening, finally.
如果你能把我们介绍给迪伦贝克将军那就太好了。
It would mean so much if you would introduce us to General Dillenbeck.
这对你很重要，还是对你的家人很重要?
It means so much to you, or it means so much to your family?
我们为伯特伦感到骄傲。
We're so very proud of Bertram.
这是他能取得的成功。
It's quite the coup he's been able to pull off.
-非常自豪。毫米。
- Very proud. - Mm.
哦，你见过将军吗?
Oh, have you met the general?
他真是一个最了不起的人。
He truly is the most wonderful specimen of a man.
湿,了。
Clammy, already.
真正的湿粘的。
Truly clammy.
她对我从来没那么冷淡过。
She never gets that clammy for me.
也许我应该多出差。
Perhaps I should travel more on business.
哦,汤姆。
Oh, Tom.
我想告诉你他是一个多么优秀的老兵，一个多么出色的医生。
I wanna tell you what a fine veteran he is and a wonderful doctor.
他值得被爱。
And he deserves love.
谢谢你，先生。
Thank you, sir.
嗨,伯特。
Hi, Burt.
-嗨。-哦，瓦莱丽。
- Hi. - Oh, Valerie.
求你了，亲爱的，你能别拍人了吗?
Please, darling, could you stop filming people?
我们在记录那晚，莉比。
We're documenting the night, Libby.
这可能是一个历史性的事件。
It could be a historical event, you know.
是的，但有些人很注重隐私。
Yes, but some people appreciate their privacy.
你不介意吧，将军?
You don't mind, do you, General?
不,不。
No, no.
——伯特?-我们应该去看看那些人。
- Burt? - We should go see those guys.
-好吗?——是的。是的，我们应该。
- All right? - Yes. Yes, we should.
瓦莱丽和她的家庭录像。
Valerie and her home movies.
这是艺术。
It's art.
碧翠丝，你愿意和我跳支舞吗?
Beatrice, will you dance with me?
我的亲爱的。
My darling.
那是Cornelius Vanderbilt。
That is Cornelius Vanderbilt.
妈妈吗?
Mother?
是的,亲爱的。
Yes, darling.
妈妈，那是康奈利·范德比尔特，他就站在爱丽丝·马博旁边。
Mother, that is Cornelius Vanderbilt, and he's standing right next to Alice Marble.
她可能会赢得美国网球公开赛。
She might win the US Open.
我的父母必须去见他们。
My parents have to meet them.
他们一直想见爱丽丝·马博。
They've wanted to meet Alice Marble the whole time.
你能等两秒钟，我们马上回来吗?
Can you just wait for two seconds and we'll come back?
你听到父亲说你要搬进来了吗?
Did you hear what Father said about you moving in?
-这不是很令人兴奋吗?-不用了，谢谢。
- Isn't that exciting? - No, thank you.
什么?你怎么…你是什么意思?
What? What do you... What do you mean?
不用了，谢谢。
No, thank you.
"不，谢谢"是什么意思?
What does "No, thank you" mean?
我等错的事等了太久。
I've waited too long for the wrong thing.
它变成了一个完全不同于以往的样子。
It turned into something very different than it ever once could be.
我觉得你可能会遭遇不幸。
I think terrible things might happen to you.
对别人说这种话……更不用说你的爱人了。
What a thing to say to anyone... let alone your beloved.
妈妈，那是科尼利厄斯·范德比尔特和爱丽丝·马博。我们去见见他们吧。
Mother, there's Cornelius Vanderbilt and Alice Marble. Let's go meet them.
没事的，伯特。
It's okay, Burt.
是啊，你还有我们。
Yeah, you still have us.
感谢上帝。我快没人了。
Thank God. I'm running out of people, fast.
几个重要人物，我相信你想见见他们。是这样吗?
Some important men who, uh, I believe you wanted to meet. Is that right?
是的。是的，我想见见他们。
Yeah. Yes, I would like to meet them.
伯伦森，我们可以去见我们说过的那些人。
Berendsen, we can meet these people that we talked about.
瓦莱丽，你跳舞的样子真可爱。
Valerie, you looked so lovely dancing.
也许你该和朋友们待在这里。
Maybe you should stay here with your friends.
汤姆·沃兹在和将军说话。
There's Tom Voze talking to the general.
哦,是的。
Oh, yes.
我一辈子都在躲着这些人。
I spent my whole life avoiding these people.
我也这么想，将军。
I feel the exact same way, General.
这些可能是比较好的，值得一试的。
These might be some of the better ones worth giving a chance.
迪伦贝克将军，我是内文斯电信的内文斯先生。
General Dillenbeck, this is Mr. Nevins of Nevins Telecommunications.
贝尔波特先生，贝尔波特化工公司，杰弗斯新闻连锁店的杰弗斯先生。
Mr. Belport, Belport Chemicals, Mr. Jeffers of Jeffers Newschain.
我们本想邀请汤姆林森先生，传奇汽车发明家，但他今晚来不了。
We wanted to have Mr. Tomlinson, legendary auto inventor, but he couldn't be here tonight.
他在慕尼黑有个很棒的公司。
He has a fantastic operation in Munich.
吉尔，我可以叫你吉尔吗?
Gil, may I call you Gil?
不。你可以叫我将军。
No. You can call me General.
他更喜欢将军。
He prefers General.
吉尔，我明白。我们理解。
Gil, I understand. We understand.
他更喜欢被称为将军。
He prefers to be called General.
最近怎么样，吉尔?
How's it going, Gil?
安德鲁·内文斯报道。你可以叫我安迪。
I'm Andrew Nevins. You can call me Andy.
好吧，我叫你安迪。你叫我将军。
Well, I'll call you Andy. You call me General.
我是来为我朋友比尔·米金斯的死算账的。
I'm here to reckon for the death of my friend Bill Meekins.
哦，那是谁?
Oh, who's that?
比尔Meekins吗?我们今晚要向他致敬。
Bill Meekins? We're honoring him tonight.
负责债券交易。
Ran the bond exchange.
当然，我对发生的事非常抱歉。
Of course, I'm terribly sorry about what happened.
我差点忘了。
I almost forgot.
女儿的悲剧。
Tragedy with the daughter.
可怕的悲剧。
Terrible tragedy.
我期待着今晚与你们谈谈海外的商业机会。
I look forward to speaking with you tonight about business opportunities overseas.
由于强有力的领导，我们在慕尼黑的工厂获得了惊人的回报。
Our plant in Munich is getting fantastic returns because of strong leadership.
知道如何把事情做好。
Knowing how to get things done.
让我们干一杯。
Let's have a toast.
是的，好的。很好。我们是三个人。
Yes, all right. Good. We are the three.
汤姆，你可以是第四个，就像我们在打高尔夫球一样。
Tom, you could be the fourth, like we're playing golf.
为了好运，我们需要一个合适的第五名。
And for good luck, we need a proper fifth.
将军?
General?
你能进来一下吗?
Won't you please step in?
敬将军。
To the general.
-将军。-敬将军。
- The general. - To the general.
一般。
To General.
说什么跟着错误的上帝回家。
Talk about following the wrong God home.
还有什么比美国企业建立的独裁政权更不美国的呢?
What's more un-American than a dictatorship built by American business?
这里有两个属性，将军，如果您想要使用它们的话。
There are two properties, General, if you should ever want to use them.
你或你的家人。
You or your family.
位于马里兰州的先锋点，贝尔波特化学品的故乡。
Pioneer Point in Maryland, the home state of Belport Chemicals.
这是你和老兵们的好去处。
A great retreat for you or the veterans.
还有一个在东汉普顿。
And another one out in East Hampton.
你和你的家人可能会喜欢。
You and your family might like it.
我会考虑的，不过我和妻子喜欢泽西海岸的小房子。
I'll think about it, though the wife and I enjoy a little place on the Jersey Shore.
也许你需要更大的想象力，将军。
Maybe you need a larger imagination, General.
所以我们才会在这里。
That's how we all ended up here.
别管这些人，将军。他们认为他们拥有世界。
Never mind these men, General. They think they own the world.
是时候继续你的演讲了。
It's time to be getting on with your speech.
我们期待您的演讲。
We're looking forward to your speech.
现在，第369届的特邀明星奥吉，出现在眼镜上。
And now, a featured star of the 369th, Auggie, on the glasses.
那是什么?
What is that?
这是苏黎世最好的创新之一。
This is one of the finest innovations from Zurich.
消除所有的痛苦和焦虑。
Removes all pain, all anxiety.
嗯?
Hmm?
所有不必要的想法占据了头脑。
All needless thoughts that occupy the mind.
我的背疼死了。
My back is killing me.
通常情况下，像我这样的人，我们不得不求助于酒精和吗啡，而这可能会导致上瘾……哦，太快了。
Now, normally, guys like me, we have to turn to booze and morphine, and that can lead to addiction... Oh, that's fast.
这是先进的。
That is advanced.
哦，那是巨大的能量。
Oh, that is tremendous energy.
-我不疼。-很好，不是吗?
- I feel no pain. - It's good, isn't it?
这很好。
That is good.
伯特，这事还没完呢。
There's more where this came from, Burt.
我想多了解一点。
I wanna know more about this.
我想要这种化合物。
I would love to have the chemical compound.
当我和我的姐妹们在Vril Society聚会时，我们会举办一个séance，在那里我们可以放松一下，它就像一种天线。
When I get together with my sisters at the Vril Society, we hold a séance where we let our hair down, and it acts as a kind of antenna.
它让我们与更伟大的种族交流。
It allows us to communicate with the greater race.
说实话，他们来自另一个星系。
Honestly, they come from a different galaxy.
这真的很吸引人。
It's truly fascinating.
现在是辛森兄弟。
And now, the Hinson Brothers.
西班牙夫人，我崇拜你从我第一次见到你的那天晚上我就想对你今晚的演讲说一些友好的建议，将军。
Lady of Spain, I adore you Right from the night I first saw you I wanted to say, for your speech tonight, General, some friendly advice.
求你了，求你了，别给他任何友好的建议。
Oh, please, please, please, don't give him any friendly advice.
是啊，有什么友好的建议吗?
Oh, yeah, well, what's the friendly advice?
今晚，人们将通过广播收听你的演讲。
Tonight, people will be listening to you on the radio.
你永远不会有更多的观众，也不会有更多的人关注你。
You'll never have a bigger audience with more excited attention from everyone.
他们会从你身上寻找灵感。
They'll be looking to you for inspiration.
记住那些为我们流血牺牲的退伍军人，记住比尔·米金斯，向他致以崇高的敬意。
Remember the veterans who have bled and died on our behalf, and remember Bill Meekins and honor him respectfully.
如果你因为米金斯的死而突发奇想，在复杂的犯罪案件中迷失了方向，这会给你带来不好的影响，我们不希望你这样，将军。
If you improvise and get lost in the woods of some complicated criminal situation over Meekins's death, it will reflect badly on you, and we don't want that for you, General.
将军说得很清楚他会尊重比尔·米金斯并说出真相。
The general was very clear about that he was gonna honor Bill Meekins and tell the truth.
嗯，我就是这个意思。
Well, that's exactly what I mean.
关注米金斯的优点。
Focus on the good qualities Meekins had.
他的安静和他的善良。
His quietness and his kindness.
这就是我打算用自己的方式去做的。
That's what I intend to do in my own way.
-那是什么?-摸摸这个。
- What is that? - Feel this.
这是海象。
This is walrus.
哦，好软。
Oh, that is soft.
一只海象因此被杀?
A walrus was killed for this?
不，先生，他是老死的。因为他做出了明智的选择，他活得又长又幸福。
No, sir, he died of old age. He lived a long, happy life because he made smart choices.
这是对你的基金会的贡献。
It's a contribution for your foundation.
我没有基金会。
I don't have a foundation.
好吧，也许你应该开始一个。我可以帮你。
Well, maybe you should start one. I can help you.
36000美元,一般。
$36,000, General.
想想你能用伯伦森医生和他的医疗创新做什么。
Think of everything you can do with Dr. Berendsen and his medical innovations.
有这么多事情要做。
So much to be accomplished.
你必须拿钱。
You have to take the money.
什么叫我得接?
What do you mean, I have to take it?
听我说。有人，而不是我，会把你的脸和你的名字，登在《纽约时报》上，然后用它来擦他们的狗屁股。
Listen to me. Someone, not me, they will take your face and your name, put it in the New York Times, and wipe their dog's ass with it.
想想你一生中所完成的一切。
Think of everything you've accomplished in your life.
它会被遗忘，被抹去。
It'll be forgotten, erased.
你会被当成老疯子被历史埋葬。
You'll be treated like an old kook and buried by history.
这就是他们能做的。做正确的演讲。
That's what they can do. Make the right speech.
不然他们会把你变成殉道者说是无政府主义者干的。
Or they'll turn you into a martyr and say an anarchist did it.
别犯比尔·米金斯那样的错误。
Don't make the mistake like Bill Meekins.
那是一起悲惨的生命盗窃案。
That was a tragic theft of a life.
西班牙夫人，我爱你
Lady of Spain, I love you
那是欣森兄弟。
That was the Hinson Brothers.
辛森兄弟，他们很棒。
The Hinson Brothers, they were great.
你不同意吗?是的。
Don't you agree? Yes.
Hinson兄弟。在做，呃，西班牙夫人。
Hinson Brothers. Doing, uh, Lady of Spain.
是的，西班牙夫人。我曾经遇到一位西班牙女士，她把我变成了一个痛苦的绅士。
Yeah, Lady of Spain. I met a lady of Spain once and she turned me into a gentleman of pain.
是的。
Yes.
现在，我要带出来的这位先生是我们团的一名医生我喜欢称他为"朋友"
Now, the gentleman I'm about to bring out right now is a doctor of our regiment and a man I like to call "friend."
请欢迎伯特·伯伦森。
Please welcome Burt Berendsen.
来吧，伯特。
Come on, Burt.
该你演讲了，伯特。伯特?
Time to give your speech, Burt. Burt?
伯特·伯伦森医生。
Dr. Burt Berendsen.
我叫伯特·伯伦森。你们大多数人都认识我。
My name is Burt Berendsen. Most of you know me.
我是埃尔米拉一个机械师的儿子。
I am the son of a mechanic from Elmira.
作为一个孩子，我们很自然地热爱这个世界。
As a child, we love the world, naturally.
我们希望全世界都爱我们。
And we hope the world loves us.
就像我的朋友哈罗德说的，有时我可能跟着错误的上帝回家了。
As my friend Harold said sometimes I might have followed the wrong God home.
但不是这个人。
Well, not this man.
他总是跟着正确的上帝回家。
He always followed the right God home.
Dillenbeck !Dillenbeck !
Dillenbeck! Dillenbeck!
Dillenbeck !
Dillenbeck!
Dillenbeck !Dillenbeck !Dillenbeck !
Dillenbeck! Dillenbeck! Dillenbeck!
Drecksgesicht !Drecksgesicht !
Drecksgesicht! Drecksgesicht!
听那些外滩混蛋的。
Listen to those Bund bastards.
流血的人，腐烂的人。
Shower of bleeders, rotters.
如果你们这些用德语对我大喊大叫的人有点勇气，你们就会表现得有尊严。
If you people shouting at me in German had any courage, you would behave with dignity.
是的!一般Dillenbeck !
Yes! General Dillenbeck!
我在三大洲参加了五场战争。
I fought in five wars on three continents.
我这辈子都被人朝我开枪。我的一生。
People shot at me my whole life. My whole life.
我了解恐惧，也知道如何面对恐惧。
I know fear, and I know facing fear.
但我真正厌恶的一件事，我真正非常厌恶的一件事，就是残忍。
But the one thing I truly detest, the one thing I truly, truly detest, is cruelty.
有人给我提供了钱，让我成为那些像你们这样的老兵的自封领袖，根据你们的民意要求，不经选举就能成为白宫的某种顾问。
I've been offered money to become the self-appointed leader of the veterans, veterans like you, to be put in the White House without an election as some sort of advisor by popular demand of you.
这些人想让我模仿一个叫墨索里尼的欧洲领导人。
These same people want me to emulate a certain European leader named Mussolini.
他们认为他是这个国家需要的那种领导人。
They think he's the type of leader that this country needs.
那种会撞死小孩却从不停车的领袖。
The type of leader who ran over a child and never stopped his car.
这类领导人的借口是，“一个人在国家事务中有什么关系?”
The type of leader whose excuse was, "What's one person in the affairs of the state?"
比尔·米金斯将军在那辆车里。
General Bill Meekins was in that car.
他是我的一个朋友。
He was a friend of mine.
他是个好人。
He was a good person.
但当他讲了这个故事，当他打算在这个舞台上再讲一遍的时候，他就变成了另一个在国家事务中毫无价值的人。
But when he told that story, when he intended to tell it again here on this stage, he became another person whose life was worth nothing in the affairs of the state.
他被谋杀了。
He was murdered.
是的，他被谋杀并蒙羞，就像我今晚在这里讲述这个故事可能会被谋杀或蒙羞一样。
Yes, he was murdered and dishonored, as I might be murdered or dishonored for telling that story here tonight.
当这种情况发生时，这将成为一个什么样的国家?
What kind of country does this become when that happens?
我成为一名海军陆战队员是为了服务于宪法，它的宗旨是让我们所有人在人类的兄弟情谊中一律平等。
I became a Marine to serve the Constitution, which intends for us all to be equal in the brotherhood of mankind.
但当有权势的人为妨碍他们的人破例时又有什么好处呢?
But what good is it when powerful people make exceptions for the people who stand in their way?
有些有影响力和权力的人喜欢看到普通人被仇恨激怒，因为这分散了我们对公平和善良的注意力。
Some people of influence and power like it when regular folks are fired up by hatred because it distracts us from the fairness and kindness.
他们不希望我们想太多，这样他们就可以从他们已经拥有的东西中得到越来越多的东西，那是巨大的财富。
They don't want us to think about too much just so they can get more and more of what they already have, which is vast wealth.
这是你的国家。
This is your country.
别让大人物把它抢走。
Don't let the big men take it away from you.
Dillenbeck !Dillenbeck !
Dillenbeck! Dillenbeck!
看，是那个人。
Look, it's that guy.
我是银行家的儿子。
I'm the son of a banker.
我是共和党人。
I'm a Republican.
-保罗和亨利在哪里?-这里不行。
- Where's Paul and Henry? - Not here.
我是个保守派。
I'm a conservative.
侦探们呢?你知道他们在哪里吗?
What about the detectives? Do you know where they are?
这里也没有。
Also not here.
这就是有钱的人只想要更多钱的那种感觉。
That's what it's like when people who have money only think about wanting much more of it.
这就是他们所想的。
That's all that they think about.
他们忘记了是你们出去保护了他们。
And they forget that you are the ones who went out and protected them.
你失去了一只眼睛或失去了生命，你的家人不得不受苦，尽管他们是把你送上战场的英雄。
You lost an eye or you lost your life, and your family had to suffer, though they were the heroes who sent you off to war.
朝我开枪的人是个懦夫。
Whoever's shooting at me is a coward.
我在世界各地都中过枪。
I've been shot at all over the world.
拿他的枪!
Get his gun!
我不害怕。我不害怕。
I am not intimidated. I am not afraid.
-你没事吧?-伯特，你没事吧?
- You all right? - Burt, are you all right?
莱姆，我没事。我很好。
Lem, I'm fine. I'm fine.
永远的暴君!
Sic semper tyrannis!
迪伦贝克是个叛徒!
Dillenbeck's a traitor!
-阻止那个人。- Tom Voze是个伟大的人!
- Stop that man. - Tom Voze is a great man!
汤姆·沃兹是个伟大的人!你有……
Tom Voze is a great man! You have...
打倒那个人。
Keep that man down.
有罪却合法。问沃兹先生!
Sinful and legal. Ask Mr. Voze!
我的祖国，美丽的自由之乡，我为你歌唱，Polizei。Polizei。
My country 'Tis of thee Sweet land of liberty Of thee I sing Polizei. Polizei.
别吵了!别吵了!到这里来。
Break it up! Break it up! Come here.
我是老兵，也是爱国者，你个傻瓜。
I'm a veteran and a patriot, you fool.
你杀了莉兹·米金斯，你个混蛋。
You killed Liz Meekins, you son of a bitch.
据我所知，她父亲也是。
And for all I know, her father too.
美国财政部!每一个人,离开!
United States Treasury! Everyone, leave!
-你没事吧?-这太可怕了。
- Are you okay? - This is terrible.
我们从没想过会发生这种事。
We never meant for anything like this to happen.
这是一种暴行。
This is an outrage.
你会被起诉的。
You're gonna be charged.
你会被起诉的，汤姆。
You're gonna be charged, Tom.
你。是的,你。
You. Yes, you.
不，先生，你搞错了。
No, sir. You are confused.
不，我没糊涂。
No, I'm not confused.
除了我自己吃的药和挨枪子，这些眼药水是我能站起来感觉不到疼痛的唯一原因。
Between my own pill and getting shot, these eye drops are the only reason I'm standing and I feel no pain.
我的天!看看这房间里发生了什么。
And holy shit! Look what's happening in this room.
一切。
Everything.
五人委员会的枪。
Gun from the Committee of the Five.
他骄傲地叫你的名字，汤姆。
He called you by your name, Tom, with pride.
我不认识那个人。
I don't know that man.
我们只是为了活命才和他搏斗。
We just fought that man for our lives.
伯特和我看到他推莉斯·米金斯。
Burt and I saw him push Liz Meekins.
他是凶手。
He's the killer.
有足够的证据。
There is enough evidence.
我很遗憾地告诉你今晚在舞台上向迪伦贝克将军开枪的人就是和米金斯在船上的那个人，他的船票是你们基金会买的。
I am sorry to say that the man who took a shot at General Dillenbeck on that stage tonight was the same man on the boat with Meekins, on a ticket purchased by your foundation.
没有必要提高你的嗓门。
There is no need to raise your voice.
你的，沃兹先生。
Yours, Mr. Voze.
汤姆，发生什么事了?
Tom, what's happening?
费用是什么?
What are the charges?
指控的对象是你和你邀请的客人。
The charges are against you and the guests you invited.
-五国委员会。-为什么?
- The Committee of the Five. - For what?
五人委员会。
Committee of the Five.
密谋贿赂美国将军。
Conspiracy to bribe a United States general.
暗杀未遂。
Attempted assassination.
阴谋推翻美国政府。
Conspiracy to overthrow the US government.
和独裁者，意大利，德国进行贸易。
Trading with dictators, Italy, Germany.
你的基金会显然与两起谋杀案有关，米金斯和他女儿。
Two murders your foundation apparently seems to be responsible for, Meekins and his daughter.
汤姆，是你干的吗?
Tom, did you do this?
我觉得米金斯的死是不对的。
I felt it was wrong that Meekins died.
那是一起悲惨的生命盗窃案。
That was a tragic theft of a life.
但他必须做点什么，因为他没有看到新的生活方式带来的机遇。
But something had to be done because he didn't see the opportunity of the new ways to live.
他不明白。米金斯不明白。
He didn't understand. Meekins didn't understand.
你明白吗?
Do you understand that?
好的。你得放慢速度。
All right. You need to slow it down.
汤姆，别告诉我你和我的药有任何关系。
Tom, please tell me you didn't have anything to do with my medication.
汤姆影响了你的医生，瓦莱丽，就像他以前对你母亲一样。
Tom influenced your doctor, Valerie, as he had done with your mother before.
-是真的吗?-有一点。
- Is that true? - A little.
一个小?
A little?
我这么做是为了你好。
I did it for your own good.
你给我下毒?
You poisoned me?
如果你想这么说，好吧。
If that's what you want to call it, fine.
我是在照顾你，为了你的最大利益。
I was looking after you, your best interests.
你太鲁莽了，像个孩子。
You're reckless, like a child.
听我说。你在欧洲到处跑，说战争的坏话?
Listen to me. You're running around all over Europe and saying bad things about the war?
和一个黑人交往。
Consorting with a Black man.
在阿姆斯特丹，和一个为你而战的自由人在一起!
Consorting with a man, a free man, in Amsterdam, that fought for you!
比如诊所，汤姆?
Like the clinics, Tom?
诊所是什么?
What clinics?
五人委员会。
Committee of the Five.
你知道我在说什么诊所，汤姆。
You know what clinics I'm talking about, Tom.
强制绝育。
Forced sterilization.
我们走着瞧吧。
We'll see about that.
我们看到了五人委员会的标志——在那里。-别撒谎了!
We saw the Committee of the Five symbol - there. - Stop lying!
汤姆有阴谋并不奇怪，但可怕的是……我的上帝。就在瓦莱丽的眼皮底下。
That Tom had an angle was no surprise, but the horror of it... My God. Right under Valerie's nose.
他们用编造的条件分散她的注意力。
They kept her distracted with the invented condition.
戈林，希特勒的得力助手，还有希特勒本人。
Goering, Hitler's right-hand man, and Hitler himself.
大多数人都不知道他是谁。
Most people didn't even know who he was yet.
汤姆甚至付钱让戈林在杰弗斯的报纸上写一篇关于雅利安新政府的专栏。
Tom even paid Goering to write a column in the Jeffers papers about the new Aryan government.
不管那是什么。
Whatever that was.
汤姆刚刚完成了带有符号的修剪。
Tom had just finished the topiary with the symbol.
你只能从上面看。
You couldn't see it except from above.
我是说，你一定是某种超级狂热的信徒才能把你的灌木弄成那样。
I mean, you gotta be some kind of super-fanatic believer to make your bushes like that.
别那样看着我，莉比。
Don't you look at me like that, Libby.
瓦莱丽,亲爱的。
Valerie, darling.
所有伟大的社会都是这样建立起来的。
All great societies are built this way.
你和你那些奇怪的雕塑生活在一个梦幻的世界里。
You live in a dream world with your strange sculptures.
这很好。你可以拿走。
And that's fine. You can have that.
但它不能使世界转动。
But it won't make the world go round.
我很高兴自己不重要，生活在一个有爱和美丽的地方。
I'm very happy to be unimportant and live in a place that has love and beauty.
艺术和爱，这才是让生命有价值的东西，而你却在创造这个巨大而可怕的未来。
Art and love, that's what makes the life worth living, while you're building this big, gigantic, terrifying future.
真是浪费你的想象力。
What a waste of your imagination.
我为我们做了很多，重建德国。
I made plenty, for us, rebuilding Germany.
我想和世界上最强大的领导人站在一起。
I wanted to stand with the strongest leaders in the world.
但我也很乐意与他们作战。
But I'm also happy to go to war against them.
另一场战争吗?但我们刚刚都做了。
Another war? But we just did all that.
你是说这些有钱人会支持独裁者还是反抗独裁者?
You mean to tell me these rich guys will support dictators or fight them?
他们只相信赚钱。
They believe in nothing but making money.
所以米金斯才被杀，就因为他不同意也不支持吗?
And that's why Meekins was killed, because he wouldn't go along with that or support it?
精神错乱!
Insanity!
我们就这样走了进去。
And we have walked right into it.
不。哦，不，不，不。
No. Oh, no, no, no.
——啊……汤姆很快就认为我们是他抓到将军的最好机会。
- Ah... - Tom quickly saw us as his best chance to get the general.
如果你能让吉尔·迪伦贝克这样的人参与你的活动，对我也有帮助。
If you got someone like Gil Dillenbeck involved with your event, it would help me to get involved.
你需要人帮忙吗?你总是……-他总是需要一个人…-瓦莱丽，-你能消停会吗?-在他面前。
So, you need someone? You always... - He always needs someone... - Valerie, - would you give it a rest? - In front of him.
你想利用这些人来抓我。
You thought you'd use these men to get me.
但我利用他们和他们的活动揭露了你阻止了你的计划至少十年。
But I used them and their event to reveal you and stop your plan for at least a decade.
也许还有两三个，希望如此。
Maybe two or three more, hopefully.
我们确实阻止了阴谋。
We did stop the plot.
这是真的。
This is true.
五国委员会没有找到他们的美国独裁者。
The Committee of the Five didn't get their American dictator.
我在国会委员会，美国人民的最高代表面前，应传票说出我所知道的……将军在国会作证，
I appeared before the congressional committee, the highest representation of the American people, under subpoena to tell what I knew of... The general testified to Congress,
他们一致认为他是对的。
and they agreed he was right.
有权势的人想要什么?
What do powerful people want?
这还不够吗?
Is it never enough?
他们做最疯狂的事。
They do the craziest things.
我的天啊!你怎么了?
Oh, my God! What's the matter with you?
你到底做了什么?
What the hell did you do?
我的天啊!瓦莱丽，你做了什么?
Oh, my God! Valerie, what have you done?
你怎么了?你做了什么?
What's the matter with you? What did you do?
我们有了起诉的所有证据，现在一切都泡影了!
We had everything we needed to prosecute, and now it's all out the window!
现在这是一个大问题。
It's a huge problem now.
是的，干得好。
Yes, well done.
汤姆，我的脸。她毁了我的脸!
Tom, my face. She ruined my face!
我没办法。它们太可怕了。
I couldn't help it. They're so awful.
女人，你疯了吗?
Woman, have you lost your mind?
我说过她是个麻烦。
I told you she was trouble.
是啊，那太蠢了，瓦莱丽。
Yeah, that was rather stupid, Valerie.
你会进监狱的，瓦莱丽。
You could go to jail, Valerie.
告诉他们真相，哈罗德。
Tell them the truth, Harold.
你没事吧，瓦莱丽?你颤抖。
Are you all right, Valerie? You're shaking.
哦，我很好。我只是想一枪打爆汤姆和莉比的脸。
Oh, I'm fine. I was just thinking about shooting Tom and Libby in the face.
——嗯。-我不会做的。别担心。
- Hmm. - I won't do it. Don't worry.
嗯，这是个好决定。感谢上帝。
Well, that's a good decision. Thank God.
是的，它会毁了一切。我们就没有案子了。
Yes, it would've bollocksed everything. We'd have no case.
你必须勇敢地面对他们，就像我们所做的那样。
You have to stand up to them, as we had done.
你必须活出真实的自己。
And you have to live your truth.
我爱哈罗德。
I love Harold.
他给了我生命中最大的幸福，伯特也是。
He's given me the greatest happiness of my life, as has Burt.
就在那儿。看那个。
There it is. Look at that.
这就是你面对这个世界的方式。
That's how you face such a world.
你必须对你的生活充满爱。
You must have love in your heart for your life.
这是爱与恨的较量。
It is love versus hate.
我爱我的生活和生活中的人。
I love my life and the people in it.
甚至比阿特丽斯。
Even Beatrice.
而且很清楚，不是葡萄牙语，我爱上了她的厄玛。
And clear, not Portuguese, I'm-in-love-with-her Irma.
弥尔顿。
Milton.
雪莉和莫蒂在办公室。
Shirley at the office with Morty.
挂毯。里面的所有东西。
The tapestry. Everything in it.
甚至我的玻璃眼睛。
Even my glass eye.
迪伦贝克的狗和我们没吃到的鱼汤。
Dillenbeck's dog and the bouillabaisse we didn't get to have.
我们每个人都有一幅挂毯，属于我们自己的歌剧。
Each one of us is given a tapestry, our own opera.
这个人和这个人。
This person and this person.
正在考虑。
Thinking about it.
光有爱是不够的。
Love is not enough.
你得为保护善良而奋斗。
You got to fight to protect kindness.
你会对人和事产生依恋。
You get attached to people and things.
他们可能会让你心碎。
And they might just break your heart.
但那就是活着。
But that's being alive.
我很不喜欢的背撑救了我。
My back brace that I so disliked had saved me from this bullet.
你这个幸运的混蛋。
You lucky bastard.
我们三个帮助阻止了这个可怕的阴谋。
And we three had helped stop this terrible plot.
我真不敢相信。
I can't believe that.
伯特·伯伦森，哈罗德·伍德曼，瓦莱丽·沃兹。
Burt Berendsen, Harold Woodman, and Valerie Voze.
混蛋,奈文斯……汤姆不会被拘留太久。
Jerks, Nevins... Tom would not stay arrested long.
那些人从来不会。
Those people never do.
和我的律师谈谈。你会看到。
Talk to my lawyer. You'll see.
五人委员会从未面临任何指控。
Committee of the Five never faced any charges.
他们消失了，就像他们会做的那样。
They disappeared, as they can do.
汤姆和他的朋友们诽谤将军。
Tom and his friends smeared the general.
这是对他们能力的警告。
It was a warning of what they were capable of.
马奎尔神秘去世，年仅37岁。
Maguire died mysteriously at the age of 37.
他知道的太多了。
He knew too much.
瓦莱丽和哈罗德在这个国家已经不安全了。
Valerie and Harold were no longer safe in this country.
一辈子的朋友就是一辈子的朋友。
Friends for life means friends for life.
你要不惜一切代价。
You do whatever it takes.
那晚我们就得把他们弄上船。
We had to get them on a boat that very night.
伍德曼，你应该…谢谢你，亨利。
Woodman, you should... Thank you, Henry.
我早就知道了。我做了决定。
I'm way ahead of you. I made my decision.
哈罗德和我一起去。
Harold's coming with me.
不，你和我一起去。
No, you're coming with me.
你会再见到我的，伯伦森医生，因为历史会重演。
You'll be seeing me again, Dr. Berendsen, because history repeats itself.
再见，老朋友。阿姆斯特丹见。
Goodbye, old friend. We'll see you in Amsterdam.
哦,不。你不会去阿姆斯特丹的。
Oh, no. You're not going to Amsterdam.
什么?
What?
盖世太保迟早会破门而入的。
It's only a matter of time before the Gestapo kicks down your door.
毫米。
Mm.
盖世太保是什么?
What's the Gestapo?
——哦。-是啊，你不会想知道的
- Oh. - Yeah, you don't wanna know.
我们会送你去更安全的地方。
We'll, uh, send you somewhere safer.
每年这个时候天气都很好。
Beautiful weather this time of year.
还有蓝头病毒的迁移。
And the blue-headed vireo migration to boot.
是的。这是一个壮观的鸟类之乡。
Yes. It's spectacular bird country.
-不是吗?——真的。
- Isn't it, though? - Really.
-是的。-我嫉妒。
- Yeah. - I'm jealous.
伯特。
Burt.
伯特，跟我们一起去吧?
Burt, why don't you come with us?
我选择留下。
I choose to stay.
谁知道呢?也许我会找到新的生活和新的爱情。-希望如此。
Who knows? Maybe I'll find a new life - and a new love. - I hope so.
因为说到爱，没有什么比清晰更美好的了。
Because when it comes to love, there's nothing quite so good as clarity.
我同意。
I agree.
我留下来是为了我的国家，这样有一天，我最好的朋友们可以回来。
I stayed to stand up for my country so that one day, my best friends could come back.
再见,伯特。
Goodbye, Burt.
再见，我的好朋友。
Au revoir, my good friend.
高兴点吧，伯特!
Be happy, Burt!
——亨利。保罗。将军。-谢谢。
- Henry. Paul. General. - Thank you.
-再见了。——弥尔顿。
- Farewell for now. - Milton.
我有点希望和朋友们一起跑步。
Part of me wished I did run with my friends.
但我没有。
But I didn't.
你希望你的心和你的子民跟随正确的神回家。
You want for your heart and for your people to follow the right God home.
阿姆斯特丹。
Amsterdam.
我在国会委员会，美国人民的最高代表面前，应传票说出我所知道的活动，我认为这些活动可能导致企图…
I appeared before the congressional committee, the highest representation of the American people, under subpoena to tell what I knew of activities, which I believe might lead to an attempt...
建立法西斯独裁政权。
to set up a fascist dictatorship.
据我所知，计划是组建一个退伍军人组织，作为恫吓或俱乐部，至少可以恐吓政府并瓦解我们的民主制度。
The plan as outlined to me was to form an organization of veterans, to use as a bluff or as a club, at least to intimidate the government and break down our democratic institutions.